Sushma: Good afternoon, everyone. Welcome to the Hechai Interviews. I'm Sushma Echa with Jamesho Foundation, Vogan Frogi.
Sushma: So, first round will be the group discussion. In this group discussion.
Sushma: We are going to discuss about the two topics. The first one is, what do you understand about us, about AFOG?
Sushma: Eshita Foundation, Gong, and A4J.
Sushma: And the second is, what do you understand from the intern, HITI intern role at Anisha Foundation? So, all the details we clearly given in the job description, and along with the Google Form, we also attach the group,
Sushma: Job description, doc link as well.
Sushma: So, this is the time to discuss about, you know, what do you understand, from, what do you understand, that, you know, that, what you referred from the document, what you referred from the job description.
Sushma: So, I'm giving you 3 to 5 minutes. If you would like to take the… gather the points, you can do that.
Sushma: So, after that, I will ask, you know, to start a topic, so you can give a start.
Sushma: I'm telling to you, please rotate your mobile into landscape.
Sushma: If you didn't turn on your video, I will remove from the meet. This is the last call from my end.
Sushma: Okay, I would like to… I have given enough time, so now let's start the discussion.
Sushma: First, let's discuss about Foji.
Sushma: Please try to speak one after one.
Sushma: don't rush Don't fight among yourself. There is no, like, you know.
Sushma: It's not a competition, just it's like, you know, sharing your views and opinions about FOG.
Sushma: First, let's, please share your opinion, sorry, share your understanding about, A4G.
Sushma: And even…
Eshita Singh: Good afternoon, ma'am, I'm Eshita.
Eshita Singh: So, I think that, if A4J, that is, AI for Good, improves collaboration, in with the…
Eshita Singh: the foundation that is based in Dili, which is a global education, nurturing.
Eshita Singh: Nurturing to the citizens of the, work, like, global stage.
Eshita Singh: The collaboration and the com- company is,
Eshita Singh: Working approximately, like, 10 years, and…
Eshita Singh: It is motivating the youth in order to,
Eshita Singh: you… in order to engage in youth programs, programs that… that could be, done with the help of AI, with the use of,
Eshita Singh: AI and the modern technology with the betterment of the city… of the…
Eshita Singh: Specifically, the youths. So far, I understand this.
Eshita Singh: And,
Eshita Singh: Apart from that, it is, it is very influencer these days, because the AI is transforming the education, and edu…
Eshita Singh: not only education, but, all over the sectors of industries, and as well as education. So, through AI, this organization is growing up, and, in that.
Eshita Singh: way it is working with the collaboration of AI and helping the youth. So, that I understand.
Sushma: So my suggestion to everyone, don't assume the things.
Sushma: And just, you know, share the things, what do you understand.
Sushma: And can you please share your resume?
Riddhi Agarwal: I wanted to add something. I… what I understood is that A4G stands for AI for Good, which is promoting ethical use of AI. Like, we have come across many cases where AI was misused.
Riddhi Agarwal: for creating, you know, inappropriate images of underage minor children. So, overall, I feel like this organization's focus is to promote ethical use of AI and to invite policymakers to build laws surrounding AI, because we do not have any prominent laws as of now.
Riddhi Agarwal: So, inviting attention to make policies surrounding AI and promoting its ethical usage to avoid any misuse of AI, spreading awareness in the community with respect to the same.
Suhani Rajoura: Ian, I would like to add, like, it's not just about education, it brings, again, like, works at intersection of technology on sustainability, mental health, and e-governance, and specifically e-governances these days.
Suhani Rajoura: very much promoted, so I think that is… like, what stands out is, it is not working in isolation, but collaborative.
Eshita Singh: Which…
Suhani Rajoura: brings in policymakers, researchers, etc, from the various fields to make an AIN better place for everyone.
Disha Sodhani: Yeah, it's basically, like, a global initiative to add on to that, which focuses more on the sustainability part, the mental health, which is very important these days, and also towards the, you know, governance part, which is, you know, and then
Disha Sodhani: AI bringing into picture, and, supporting all this, I think, yeah, that's what AA4G stands for.
Sowmiya K R: I need to add a few things related to major activities they have performing for A4G.
Sowmiya K R: First is organizing international AI Governance Conference and other symposiums also publishing research policies and recommendations. Now, they have been partnering with universities and government industry-oriented platforms, and they have running fellowship programs, internships, and growth
Sowmiya K R: youth-related programs also. Now, they have been increasing collaboration on AI for the solutions of aligning with the UN sustainable goals, that is, SDG goals, that is currently, they have following right now, and
Sowmiya K R: It's an impact, it's a Collaborative, it's a Anisha Foundation global initiative that promotes ethical AI that is the most core platform of demos, and it's also, they are trying to build a responsible AI governance through the sustainability and, the social impact they have bringing together through academia.
Sowmiya K R: policy makers, as they have mentioned, and industry. And the most critical thing, what I have saw, is that they're making youth to ensure that AI serves humanity.
Nitish chaudhary: According to me, A4G is an organization that helps people and organizations use AI responsibly to solve real-life problems while making sure that it is safe and fair. For example, in the field of education, climate change, and many other topics.
Nitish chaudhary: So that is my understanding about the A4G.
Ranjana Sharma: Yeah, I want to add one more point as well, that Anisha Foundation is an NPO, that is a non-profit organization, and it works on creating positive social impact.
Ranjana Sharma: And, they created by working on education, youth empowerment, and sustainability, innovation, and etc. And about A4G, so AI for good to definitely create a positive impact.
Ranjana Sharma: Through, by using air.
Bhumika K: Adding on to this point, I would like to add that, Anisha Foundation adds, both, Wong and A4G, as of right now. So, Wong also promotes DEI, which is a part of psychology. They make sure everyone feels included, and then they have, climate change, sustainability as a part of their initiative.
Bhumika K: Which, I believe is a very motivating aspect, because people should feel included in any workplace, and that is a part of their initiative. And also, they're using AI for mental health, and as we all know, AI could be used as an immediate help. When people are in immediate psychological, if they need immediate psychological help.
Bhumika K: These, AI tools can, assist us, like chatbots can help us in giving the contact details or national helpline numbers, so that they can also help them. And apart from this, they're also promoting sustainability and, what, sustainability and, ethical use of AI, because we all use AI irresponsibly.
Bhumika K: We just, outwardly post whatever we want, whatever answers we require, and then we don't, think about the consequences of it.
Bhumika K: With respect to AI, because our data might end up in dark web, so this, organization is basically helping us to, promote mental health, and also, they are also helping us to, you know, ensure that we contribute to any, future SDG.
Eshita Singh: because I don't…
Bhumika K: think there is, schools. Let's say, because people still discriminate between men and women in workplace right now. Still, there is glass ceiling effect. That term still exists, and people still, subtly discriminate, you know, genders, genders in workplaces also. So I think it is a great initiative on the part of A4G.
yashna: We are agreeing with whom.
Sneha Patil: According to me.
yashna: Like, obviously, A4G and Wong are the two, two key initiatives of Eshita Foundation, like, Wong stands for Voice of Young, Young Generation, New Young Generation, which, like, empowers the young generation to voice their opinions, their concerns, their problems.
yashna: or whatever we are facing. And, A4G, like, AI for Good, like, 3 main points, AI for governance, mental well-being, and socioeconomic sustainability, which, like, helps new entrepreneurs to start their, startup business and, like, like, have a push from.
yashna: them, and, like, it's a very good initiative, like, for mental well-being and for governance. They make sure that the AI is used ethically, they are not, like, obviously in this phase, AI used in very inappropriate ways. Like, everyone can, have an experience or have seen someone's experience, which is not, you want to have. It is not a good experience.
yashna: So.
yashna: it makes sure that AI is used ethically, and it is used in a fair manner, and Eshita Foundation, like, it is a non-profit organization which focuses on creating social impact, and it works in areas such as
yashna: sustainability, and uses AI for the, like, social good, using AI technology.
Swetcha: I believe everyone has covered most of the details about this internship opportunity and what A4G stands for. I would just like to sum it up, since everyone has already covered up most of the details, and I don't think we're missing anything as of now.
Swetcha: So, A4G is, basically an initiative by Umisha Foundation, and
Swetcha: It also has another initiative that is Voice of the New Generation. So, stands for basically three important things, that we are using AI for good, AI for sustainability, and AI for mental health, and this is the gist of everything that's been said so far, I believe.
Swetcha: Thank you.
Nitish chaudhary: So, agreeing to my friends, I would like to add one point, that Eshita Foundation actually brings together, for example, the companies, officials, universities, to discuss and work on the AI-related issues. Along with this, organizing events such as conferences, workshops, and discussion on the responsible AI, and also promoting the responsible AI that is safe, fair, and transparent.
Garima: If…
Ranjana Sharma: Yeah, one more thing, I want to…
Garima: for Good Impact Collaborative is one of the flagship initiatives of Umesha Foundation. Its vision is to ensure that artificial intelligence is developed and used in a responsible, ethical, and human-centered way.
Garima: It brings together students, researchers, policy makers, and industry experts to address challenges related to AI governance.
Garima: Mental well-being, and socio-economic sustainability.
Garima: The initiative also promotes collaboration through research, policy, discussion, fellowship.
Garima: partnership and events. Rather than, focusing on the… only on technology, A4G aims to ensure that AI benefits society, protects human dignity, and, supports sustainable development.
sneha : According to me, AI is the fastest growing technology. I want to learn about AI. Can you grow the business? And, collaborates with many other apps. Right now, AI is the fastest company.
sneha : The topic is diversity.
Sushma: Please hold on. The topic is diverting, so, it's like, please focus about either A4G or Wong. That's it.
Sushma: what, like, you know, just focus about us, what we do, what do you understand?
Riddhi Agarwal: Bomb.
sneha : AI4G impacts collaborating in organizations that promotes collaboration. It takes AI by working with business, government, and education institutions.
Olivia Giri: From what I have understood, Eshita Foundation is a purpose-driven organization that aims to create positive social impact by empowering, like, people and building strong communities.
Olivia Giri: What makes it unique to me, that it doesn't just focus on social work in the traditional sense, it also embraces innovation and technology to solve real-world problems. One of the ways it does through is FOG, or AI for Good.
Olivia Giri: I see APOG as an initiative.
Olivia Giri: That, like, encourages the ethical and responsible use of artificial intelligence. It's not about using AI for technology.
Olivia Giri: Alone, but about using it to improve people's lives. I found it interesting that F4G focuses on areas like AI governance, mental well-being, and socioeconomic sustainability, showing that technology and human values can go hand in hand.
Olivia Giri: So, overall, I feel like that Omisha Foundation and FOG share a common vision.
Olivia Giri: Using, like, innovation, collaboration, and people-centric thinking to create a meaningful and lasting impact.
Shrobana Sarkar: So, I want to share my view on AI, A4G Impact Collaborative is an AI for Good organization which uses the AI to solve the social problems. They focus on areas like sustainability, mental health, and responsible AI. So, this company works with researchers, policy makers, and industry experts to develop the AI
Shrobana Sarkar: AI solutions that can create a positive impact on society. I like their, like, I like the mission of using the technology to improve people's, lives while ensuring AI is used responsibly.
Sujitha S: It's a non-profitable organization, and, it works on, education and equal opportunities, and it also, works on a sustainability and a climate action also.
Sujitha S: It's, responsible for AI for good source, and, it's also encouraging the youth leadership and voluntary.
Sujitha S: And, it also, doing diversity and inclusion of innovatives.
Riya: Okay, according to…
Ananya Yadav: OG impact.
Ananya Yadav: The 4G Impact Collaborative is an initiative that promotes the ethical use of artificial intelligence to create positive social impact. It works with committees and organizations to develop AI-based solutions in areas such as healthcare, education, sustainability, governance, and social development.
Sowmiya K R: I need to add a few more points here.
Sowmiya K R: Let's think about it in this way. Every major decision on our planet's future, from climate policies to sustainable targets, gets made in a room full of people who all treated with the time of those consequences were arrived.
Sowmiya K R: Wong, the voice of new generation, exists through that challenge. It is a youth movement under Omscha Foundation. Its over premises is increasingly simple. The generation…
Sowmiya K R: Initial problem should have, say, in how it's revolved. It's not just being how we handle the bills of it. So Wong does the two things at once. First, it educates ink people.
Sowmiya K R: I think it educates young people, not just the work of creating awareness campus or grounded them in the actual UN Sustainable Development. So goals they have understood here is the CAIC, and the second is more important and interesting part is, I think, that it opens them an actual platform to be heard by the policymakers at the institution.
Sowmiya K R: Not a classroom, a microphone.
Sowmiya K R: I would also call it as the difference between teaching someone to swim or actually letting them into the pool. Lots of the organization stops at the education.
Sowmiya K R: work really best. It evades in our knowledge without voice, just in our homework.
Sowmiya K R: It doesn't change anything unless someone's actually listening.
Sowmiya K R: And it makes something sense that Work sits right alongside A4J under the same foundation. A4J's asking how we build AA responsibility, and WARG is…
Sowmiya K R: Asking a sharper question underneath that, who gets excited of what responsibility even means? It answers the people who actually have to live in the world we are building.
Sowmiya K R: Not just those making the decisions.
Sushma: Are you reading from somewhere else?
Sowmiya K R: No, ma'am, can I share my screen now?
Sushma: No worries. I don't want to cross-check that. I'm just conforming with you.
Sushma: That's it.
Sushma: Alright. See, guys,
anam anwar: Mem…
Sushma: Just hold on, let's… let me shift the topic.
Sushma: Lastly, for one minute, Anything that… You would like to cover?
Sushma: New point.
Sushma: Please don't, you know, repeat. So, most of people are not really onto the map. You are, like, okay near to that. So, if anything you would like to add from your end, I just want to hear any new points.
Riddhi Agarwal: I feel like as a…
Riddhi Agarwal: youngsters, it is really important to be more aware about the society, the environment, and the social changes, such as, you know, the climate change and how it's being affected. So beyond what education schools have to offer, I feel like Anisha Foundation is providing an excellent platform
Riddhi Agarwal: To connect the young minds and to bring like-minded people together to initiate more conversations about the environmental change and how they must be more responsible growing up to ensure that, you know, they live in a better, world overall.
sneha : Okay, above.
Bhumika K: Also, another, point I would like to add, both, Umisha Foundation and, Bhumik, they also promote, mental health, because, oftentimes we cons… in India, it is considered a stigma to talk about mental health openly. So, I believe, and also including DEI, which is, like, an important aspect.
Bhumika K: to make everyone feel included in workplace, because we often treat people who are different. Let's say a neurodiverse individual… we treat someone who's neurodivers, who has ADHD, autism has someone who's different, and we see them differently, but that is not the case. They're making us feel that.
Sushma: Our mental well-being, our mental well-being…
anam anwar: Change the advanced technology solutions, including AI as a tool, and also empowered program for marginalized groups.
Sushma: I didn't you?
sneha : It is so…
ashi: I believe…
sneha : It takes, transfer, and include AI to reach.
Sushma: Please hold on.
Bhumika K: Burn fact.
ashi: Technology and peoples work together, they can create meaningful and lasting change.
Bhumika K: It's fine, vision.
anam anwar: also work as a gender diversity and inclusion has been recognized through national awards like SEBRA Initiatives Awards.
Nitish chaudhary: Fantastic.
PEARL: So, ma'am, Bhesha Foundation aims to safeguard human values as whole. Not only it considers any individual, but whole human values it considers.
Nitish chaudhary: So, at last, I would like to conclude my point by saying that A4G, that is, AI for good, uses artificial intelligence to solve the real-world problems that is ethical, safe, and beneficial for the society. The fields can be education, climate change, and
Nitish chaudhary: The healthcare. For example, I would like to give you an example. If a hospital used the artificial intelligence to detect the disease using the X-ray.
Nitish chaudhary: So, they will ensure that the artificial intelligence provide the accurate results. Not only provide the accurate results, it also protects the customer data, which is ethical and safe. So, this is what I understand by using artificial intelligence for a good way that is ethical, safe, and beneficial for the society also.
Sushma: Alright, please hold on. I would like to close this discussion.
Sushma: Now, please, you know, start discussing what do you understand about HR internal, which is mentioned in the job description. Please don't assume the things.
Sushma: So, just share what do you understand from that. That's it.
yashna: For HR internship role, what the company is founding, like, they're aspiring for an HR intern who can handle the roles and responsibility of recruitment, onboarding, all the documentation work, and using the AI to, like, for the recruitment search or sourcing candidates.
yashna: For, like, you can…
yashna: Like, the important thing is understanding the employees, employees' engagement, how they can engage in a much better way, all the, sourcing the candidates according to the job description, which is a main important part, which is very necessary to find a right candidate for the,
yashna: company, and, checking the job description, and according to that, finding the candidates is a necessary, part of HR. And, after the, like, if you shortlist a candidate, and then onboarding them to the organization, explaining them everything about the organization, and, grievance handling is a, another important part of the HR.
yashna: If any employee is having, any trouble from any senior or organization, you can…
yashna: employee will come to the HRA only, and the HR has to handle the grievance. And…
yashna: Other thing is,
Nitish chaudhary: Enricho.
yashna: Yup.
anam anwar: I didn't even…
Nitish chaudhary: primary… is to look after the lifecycle management.
Nitish chaudhary: The primary role of HR intern is to look after the lifecycle manage… employee lifecycle management from the recruit front, ensuring the screening regime is scheduling interviews. After that, onboarding the employees, training, then learning and development.
Nitish chaudhary: Also, tracking their performance management and using the artificial intelligence into the HRMS software to improve the efficiency of an organization. Also, looking after the company policies and also doing the grievance management, that is the primary role of an HR intern.
Sowmiya K R: I need to add two roles, because I read the job description through a portal, a job portal, which is called a LinkedIn. I have seen there is two roles, that is, one is central operations and people management, another is community building, and
Sowmiya K R: team culture building, I think so. So, an HR operations
Sowmiya K R: We need to focus more on recruitment, onboarding, screenings, and performance management, and also OPM, which is organizational performance management related of tasks we need to do. That is the first and primary roles comes in HR organization and people management. Second is the most important, that is community buildings and team culture focus. It focuses on how we can be able to deliver to the team, and how collaborative we are, and how much ownership we're taking as the part of
Sowmiya K R: A4J organizations. And here, being the… it just brings a meaningful conversation of how we actually
Sowmiya K R: Other communities, and how we take the initiatives, and how strong we are
Sowmiya K R: building a relationship with our colleagues. So these are the two important roles which I have got from the GA.
Bhumika K: So, adding on to the point, what I believe is, we do recruitment, onboarding, HR documentation, performance management, and then employee engagement, learning, and development. But why do we do this? All of this we do…
Bhumika K: That we can ensure that
Bhumika K: We align the employees' goals with the organizational goals. Ultimately, we want all of this. We ensure that the employee stays engaged, and throughout the entire duration, they are engaged, and they can, you know, contribute effectively to the organization. And also, we ensure that everyone feels included, and that is what community building is. We ensure that everyone's voice is heard, everyone feels included. We give, we ensure that
Bhumika K: Their, problems and issues are resolved, and we individually track their performance and ensure that they're satisfied with their job, so that they can effectively and…
Bhumika K: physically and mentally, they're able to contribute to the organization. That is the ultimate goal that we all have, right, as an HR, because we want to align our, the employees' goals with the organization's goals.
Eshita Singh: Yes, Bhumika, you're right. As you said, that HR roles are how HR roles are different from each other, but all that processes that, everyone until date said, that recruitment, screening, onboarding, and all that, is important for a company or an organization because
Eshita Singh: The HR is important in between, like, it's bridged between the employee and the company. That helps to communicate what the problems an employee faces. Also, at the same time, what company wants from the employee.
Eshita Singh: So, the HR intern or HR role in the company is measuredly to communicate and bridge the
Eshita Singh: things, the information that a company wants to tell to the employee, an employee want to tell to the company. So this is all about it.
Olivia Giri: From my understanding… This is not…
sneha : Thank you, Anna.
sneha : It's my time.
Swetcha: Already.
sneha : They want to someone who has an HR employment engagement, team culture, and AI with HR. HR helps to recruitment and interview, assist on onboarding new employees, supporting employees' engagement activities, communications with an employee, helping resolving employees' concerns, and focusing about supporting the performance and
sneha : management.
Olivia Giri: From my understanding.
Olivia Giri: It's much more than a traditional HR internship.
Olivia Giri: The role is not limited to recruitment or administrative tasks.
Olivia Giri: It focuses on, like, enabling people, building a positive work culture, and helping the organization achieve its mission through its people. The first aspect is recruitment and onboarding, where HR helps attract the right talent, and ensures a smooth onboarding experience, and makes new members feel welcomed and aligned with the organization's
Olivia Giri: values. Another important responsibility is employee engagement and communication. I believe HR plays a key role in creating an environment where people feel heard
Olivia Giri: motivated and connected. This includes, handling, employee concerns, gathering feedbacks, and along with encouraging collaboration across teams.
Olivia Giri: What I found especially interesting is the emphasis on AI in HR. The role encourages researching AI tools and trends to make HR processes more efficient. However, I think AI should support HR professionals by reducing repetitive tasks.
Olivia Giri: While empathy, relationship building and decision making should always remain human. The role also highlights, like, performance management and organizational alignment.
Olivia Giri: To me, this means helping individuals understand their goals, supporting their growth, and ensuring everyone's efforts contribute to the organization's overall mission. So, I really like the focus on community building and ownership. It's about creating a culture
Olivia Giri: where people take initiative, collaborative, like, effectively, and feel a sense of belonging. I believe these are qualities that help both individuals and the organizations grow together.
Nitish chaudhary: Overnight.
Ranjana Sharma: Then it's a lot.
Garima: Signature.
Ranjana Sharma: turn, I will take points.
Garima: People in the organization as they, provide a bridge between the, top level of the company and the employees, as they, communicate with, with all the informations and all the important,
Garima: notices, which circulates among the, employees in the company. Hr team, the support which HR team provides to the companies, of recruitment, onboarding.
Garima: Employee engagement, HR operations, and performance management. Coordinating interviews, maintaining HR records, communications, with com- candidates, and,
Garima: team members supporting employee engagement activities and contributing to, creating a positive work culture is also one of the… is also most important, most important thing which, HR, does in the company, and, that,
Sujitha S: Actually, water…
Nitish chaudhary: Don't you agree with me? I would like to say that…
Riya: Seen, collected, and detected.
ashi: And working together while supporting recruitment and employee management.
Riya: Because, Agar team acha se kami kariki team mein, unity nahi hogi. Toh kasi sabhalaya.
Riya: Actually, what I thought is, see,
Sujitha S: employee has to be sustainable in their work, so if there has to be sustainable in their work, there has to be psychologically stable. If they are not stable, and the HR has to take the role, and they have to deal with the employees to sustain their mental health.
Sujitha S: And then, only, we can see all those things. See, if they are not, psychologically stable, then
Sujitha S: they may, quit the organization, then we have to… again, we have to recruit the peoples, so it will be an ongoing process. The thing is.
Sujitha S: the HR has to seek whether the employee is okay with this organization, whether he has… he or she has any conflicts between the employees or between the employers. So, we have to see that, and then we have to give their, motivation and other things. That's it.
sneha : Adding to your point, building good relations with team members, encouraging team members, collaborating, organization engagement activities, helping creating positive and,
sneha : clear, culture. Motivating team members, participating and inventing the team members, it will be less,
sneha : There will be less conflict.
Swetcha: I really like the highlight on the mental health aspect of, HR that Sujitha, ma'am, put. So, I really liked about this opportunity is that they
Swetcha: As for someone who is from an organizational psychology background, so this was one of the requirements in their hiring procedure, I believe.
Swetcha: Or maybe it was a preference, but it is very important when you are working in an HR, you understand people. So HR is a very people-centered role. So, when you are working with HR, you need to understand, and you have to have some sort of empathy.
Swetcha: And that is when HR moves the smoothest. It is more than just hiring people and recruitment, it is related to understanding people and making human connections, and that is why I really love the point about having an organizational psychologist as someone working in HR.
Bhumika K: Thank you.
Bhumika K: Adding on to strictness…
Nitish chaudhary: I'd also like to say that the secondary group, when the charge is to…
Riya: Very important, because healthy and happy employers perform better. HR should create a sporty work.
ashi: Environment, encourage open communication, reduce stress, and help employee…
Riya: maintain in a healthy work-life balance. Because balance is… Important.
ashi: You know.
Sushma: Okay, Stevie, I'll be with you.
Sowmiya K R: I need to highlight a few case studies related to this.
Sushma: Now, please discuss about, please focus the key responsibilities, what we mentioned in the job description, and the primary role and second role mentioned in the job description. So please talk about that. It's, like, what you understand.
Ranjana Sharma: From the job description, the very first thing that I… I understand from the job description is that, as an HR, we should do work. The very first thing is recruitment, like posting job openings and shortlisting candidates.
Ranjana Sharma: and scheduling interviews. And the second thing is onboarding, like familiarizing the new interns or the new employers with the company's rules and regulations.
Ranjana Sharma: Then the very third, thing is employee engagement, like, motivating them continuously, so they work, with, they work for the organization, very productively. And the fourth thing is employee communication, communicating with the employees well, and understanding that if they have any issues, then understanding them. And the performance management, definitely, tracking that, their performance is aligning with the
Ranjana Sharma: organizational goals or not, and AI and HR means that, continuously searching or learn or research AI tools that helps us, that helps that make HR work easier.
Ranjana Sharma: And then team building to create a friendly and collaborative work environment, and the organizational performance, definitely, that, yeah, teams stay aligned, and encouraging them continuously, so the organizational goals can be achieved, effectively.
Shrobana Sarkar: Yeah, I wonder…
Bhumika K: Adding on to roundabouts.
Nitish chaudhary: HR, in turn, is to build a positive environment where they understand the individual strength of the team and collaborate so that they can collaborate each other and drive the business growth.
Nitish chaudhary: The main work of… in the secondary role is to build the meaningful relations with the core team members and the contributors, and also that create a sense of ownership and belonging among the community's members, so that they can support and collaborate with each other to ensure the business growth and a positive work culture.
yashna: So, I would like to add one point, that compliance… compliance is also a main… a key responsibility of the HR, such as labor law compliance, which, HR has to ensure that the payment or the salary of the employee has been, given to them and has been received by them at time, and if there is any overtime payment, or is there any reduction in their salary.
yashna: It should be transferred to the employee. Second would be the attendance and the leave of the employees. It should be managed, and it should be, like, it should be a proper track, a track for the HR, so that, there should not be any, like, if they are absent and you have marked present, so it is not fair. And the third would be POSH compliance, prevention of sexual harassment, which is enabled
yashna: which is, which has a community in almost every organization, where you have a proper POSH, policy and community, and you can report if there is any harassment has happened to you. You have to, you can, like, go to the Posh community, and these are some compliance which are very important for HR to know.
Bhumika K: Adding on to,
PEARL: also takes care that the local labor laws are also taken care of, and the organization is working for the welfare of the people, and the safety regulations should be maintained, and there should be clear communication between the employees and the.
Bhumika K: Adding on to everyone's point, so I just wanted to convey that
Bhumika K: The, most of the HR internships, mostly focus on, recruitment, onboarding, but this one was more people-oriented.
Bhumika K: And we focus on people, so that in this internship, we also have the opportunity to, you know, develop employees, through all the process from the beginning, because it starts from recruitment, and then onboarding, and then we maintain their performance, and then we help them with their grieviances. And then till they're offboarding, this entire internship takes care of. It covers all the aspects.
Bhumika K: provides us the opportunity to research about HR trends and AI tools. And hence, it is also providing us the opportunity to constantly learn and grow, so that we are also not disengaged, because if we are disengaged, how are we supposed to motivate the employees? How are we supposed to, you know, engage them, and then help them contribute to the organization effectively? So I believe
Bhumika K: This is a great opportunity, because it also provides us the ability to learn and grow.
Sowmiya K R: How can I… If you are to be forced.
Sujitha S: development, we have…
Sowmiya K R: guests.
Sujitha S: That's cute.
Sowmiya K R: I don't want it to be more generic. I wanted to be more specific about this particular internship of F4G. Here, it all… I already mentioned this because it have two roles. One is primary and another is secondary. Here, the primary role speaks more about HR operations and how we manage people, how we engage them. Here, it includes from recruitments to all of the things, what we have already discussed. Like, it has two things, one is PM and OPM, performance management, and we also think about organizational
Sowmiya K R: smartphone management. Like, the individual goals need to be aligned with the organization goals as well. And the secondary role is community building and team cultural building. As HR, I believe it is a core performance, because we need to communicate with all the people to align the organizational goals, their individual goals also.
Sowmiya K R: So here, here, what I see as an interesting part is they have mentioned a word that you can engage with their initiatives. So we are not only being interested in only HR, we can also be able to do what STHE goals and other related activities we can be able to focus. So this gives us a broader perspective of working in this company.
Sujitha S: I thought, was he, actually, after selection…
ashi: About, helping the whole organization perform better.
ashi: It is not only about individual performance, but also about teamwork, communication, clear goals, and continuous improvement.
Riddhi Agarwal: I'd like I feel that…
Sujitha S: Mehta.
Riddhi Agarwal: in HR, it's important to ensure that everyone gets a fair opportunity. Like, I've noticed, even during this interview, a lot of people have a lot to say, but not everyone is getting a fair opportunity to, you know, put their point of view across.
Riddhi Agarwal: So, you know, ensuring that everyone in the company gets a fair chance to be seen and heard, and creating a sense of approachability where people do not shy away from raising any grievances. I feel like that is extremely important, to be fair and to create an inclusive
Sushma: Comment here. See, if you go to the Comptative exam.
Sushma: There will be a limited time.
Sushma: If you're not feeling well, will they do the time for you?
Riddhi Agarwal: No, no.
Sushma: No.
Sushma: So, in this competitive world, so, to filter the candidates as a HR, you need some second criteria to filter the candidates. It's not fairness here. If you, if you look into the fairness.
Sushma: Suppose, just can you please answer this situation? If the perf, like, you know, if the individual in the organization, need the job, they, they, due to some financial,
Sushma: needs something. But, you know, that performance… that individual performance is not up to the mark, even though after giving number of trainings also.
Sushma: And what's the organization Disha is, you know, Telnet in Mohan.
Sushma: So, as a HR, like, what do you do?
Ranjana Sharma: overflow.
Swetcha: Wednesday.
Eshita Singh: is more eligible, not to see that whether the candidate is, like, showing
Eshita Singh: mercy is not the work that company… that… by which the company can work. So, the one who is more eligible, and one more… who is more outspoken and can put the points, whatever the person wants to say, and also what the person says, it fulfills that
Eshita Singh: work and everything that is asked by the person. So, there is no point in industry, there is no point of sympathy.
Eshita Singh: But we can say… we can do empathy, but there's no point of sympathy.
Riya: Restick and Patience invitation.
Riddhi Agarwal: It is important to prioritize the…
Sushma: But me as well.
Riddhi Agarwal: interest.
Eshita Singh: Yes, ma'am.
Swetcha: The biggest side.
Sushma: Definitely as a HR, if the organization's decision is not aligned to the organization policies.
Riya: And the ethics, definitely, like, you know, we have to raise our voice, or we can do that.
Riya: If the particular behavior, individual behavior of the employees, is not aligned to the organization policies, what will you do?
Riya: We will definitely terminate them.
Riya: Like, is it.
Sushma: Nice!
Riya: Are we showing any, like, you know, kindness or sympathy? Because, you know, we had to give them opportunity, you know, like.
Sushma: Let it dead, they will change.
Riya: Of course, we may give one to two chances. For the whole life, we can't do any chances.
Riya: So for… see, while… while you are judging anyone.
Riya: The interview process, or any process, any processes, like, you know, wear shoes from the organization side.
Sushma: And wear a show from as an individual as well.
PEARL: How much fairness.
Ranjana Sharma: The organization side.
Riya: disabled.
Riya: Alternate.
Sujitha S: Actually, we have to give them three times, we have to give them memo for 3 times. If it is not working, then we have not heard it from the organization, right?
Swetcha: This is what the probation period is for.
Sujitha S: We can't, at first, we can't be able to terminate them, we have to give a chance, we have to give them what is…
Swetcha: The patient field is used exactly to understand if the employee is compatible with the company.
Sushma: We need to motivate them, encourage them. After doing number of…
Riya: You know…
Sushma: practices. It's still that behavior.
Sushma: And the performance is not optimal, definitely, the restaurant will be termination.
Riya: Excellent.
Bhumika K: But ma'am, can I add one more point? Because if an.
Sushma: Thank God.
Bhumika K: feels disengaged, a well-performing employee feels disengaged, then what do you do? Do you immediately terminate them? You should give a chance, right? Like, you have to, like.
Anisha Pati: Go ahead and sweet.
Bhumika K: Beautiful.
Swetcha: Without consequences won't help, there need to be some sort of consequences if the employer's performance is not up to the mark.
Ranjana Sharma: Ma'am, I want to add one point, actually. There is a term called training and development that comes under HR responsibilities. So, after giving continuous training, and still they are not performing well, then it's good to terminate.
Nitish chaudhary: According to me, I would like to give you a point here, that if you have higher standards, so definitely there would have been some certain skills on that basis we have hired.
Riya: So if their, performance is not up to the mug, there can be some issues.
Riya: We have to find that, what is concerning them. And if we try to solve them, and his improvement, his performance improves, then definitely he's a suitable. If not, then definitely we should terminate him. So that's the thing.
PEARL: But it's not… But after that, there is also…
Sujitha S: See?
PEARL: everything.
Sushma: Can you please hold on, see?
Bhumika K: Just please…
Riya: Yes, the discussion is going out of the box.
Sushma: I just, like, you know, it… we cannot, as a HRS event, like, you know, we cannot stay…
Bhumika K: It's okay.
Sushma: Any decision also, because the decision may vary person to person, situation to situation.
Bhumika K: sold?
Sushma: The other thingies?
Sushma: I don't, want to prolong this discussion. I would like to stop this. And most of your understanding about the organization is not really up to the mark, so I just want to give a brief about us.
Sushma: Thereafter, about the role, then, we will filter the candidates, and we'll, the good-to-go candidates will be going forward with the next staff.
Sushma: So, if I talk about the Omisha Foundation, see, Eshita Foundation is having the two initiatives. The first initiative is Wong, Voice of New Generation.
Sushma: And here, currently, we are not much active in this one of, like, you know, voice of new generation, but, like, you know, we, we focus 12 to 18-age group of school-going students.
Sushma: So, we provide them a platform to raise their voices towards the sustainability challenges. So that, so we organize, so far, 7 Sustain Spark events, 7 versions of event… Sustain Spark events.
Sushma: And we are going to organize a few more versions and other extend events as well, so that they can have a platform to raise their voices.
Sushma: So here, we don't believe in teaching and preaching them.
Sushma: Instead of that, we believe them, Inspiring, motivating them through gamification.
Sushma: So, that what are the innovative solutions they're coming towards, the sustainability challenges. So, through the motivation, from gamification, so they can put that…
Sushma: ideas into actions from the locality itself. So, the change will come from their end. So, we believe that they are the future change makers.
Sushma: And whatever the people who join in our community from 12 to 18 age group, we call them WOM staffs. So this is about the worm, and also this WOM is also focused into 17 SDG goals.
Sushma: So that, you know, all, so that the change, development, everything.
Sushma: expecting to start from the 12 to 18H group of that generation. So, if you ask why you focus that generation, because already
Sushma: the present generation is already spoiled. If we say anything, like, you know, this is right, this is to avoid, this is, you know, causing the… so they won't change their minds. Their minds are already fixed, like, you know, but when… when we start changing fresh minds so that they can change the future generation.
Sushma: So, that's the reason we targeted the 12 to 18 group of school-going students in the Wong initiative. And if I talk about the A4G, Air For Good Impact, Collaborate. So, the name itself suggests that A4G is Air For Good.
Sushma: Impact Collabor.
Sushma: So, if I talk about the, vision.
Sushma: So, we, like, you know, we believe that AI becomes…
Sushma: becomes a natural extension of human goodness. So, it should be our vision that we have to see that AI should become the human extension, natural extension of human goodness, so that we can enhance the compassion, equity, well-being.
Sushma: So that, you know, rather than replacing the, human values, so we… we don't want to replace the human values by using the AI. This is the vision.
Sushma: whereas coming to the mission. So, we would like to collaborate with
Sushma: Policy makers, researchers, global leaders, donors, institutions who are working towards AI for good.
Sushma: So that, you know, all together can co-create the human-centered solutions. So this is our mission. So we support each individual's communities, which impacted by AI-driven, that, you know, all together can change,
Sushma: The three focus areas, which, we are having the three focus areas, which is governance of AI, A for mental well-being, and A for socioeconomic sustainability.
Sushma: If I talk about the AI governments.
Sushma: So, in this, focus area, we work to make sure AI is developed and used in fair, ethical, and responsible way.
Sushma: So, we, like, you know, all the policy makers, so we would like to collaborate, like, you know, we're collaborating with the policy makers, researchers, so that, you know, all together can get the ethical policy making, and…
Sushma: Like, you know, we promote the responsible and ethical use of AI, and we explore the AI barrage when people and communities have a volume, have a voice.
Sushma: how, like, you know, AI is governed, so that, you know, all bringing together in this, like, for instance, like, you know, experts which is in policy making, government, institutions, organizations, and the individual citizens.
Sushma: So, what are the ethical policy make… what are the ethical policies that they're coming through policy makers, requesting the government to put into the practice in an ethical way? So that, it's a collaboration with government as well, and organization to involve citizens and policy makers, so that we can create A policies.
Sushma: That can benefit to everyone in ethical and fair way.
Sushma: And whereas coming to the A for mental well-being, few people understood… most of people, misunderstand about the A for mental well-being, so there were various, like, you know, it's been, like, you know, our focus, A for mental well-being, our focus is
Sushma: Mostly, we help people build sustainable careers and livelihoods with support of AI.
Sushma: So, if, if I, let me tell this instance,
Sushma: Like, you know, we, here, like, you know, hear AI mental well-being.
Sushma: We help the people, individuals, who affected AI changes discover their strengths, and we build a meaningful future.
Sushma: Here, because of AI, for instance, 4 are required, to do the work.
Sushma: well, automation tools, in… come into place, so that instead of 4 members, 4 members, maybe 2 or 1 is required. So the rest of people may, don't have any opportunities
Sushma: to survive in the world. So the people who are not finding the opportunities to survive in the world, for them, you're providing a platform and tool to, you know, to find the opportunities by their own.
Sushma: So that they can also build a solar entrepreneurship with the help of AI.
Sushma: they can do their small business with the help of AI.
Sushma: And with their niche skills, they can also find their new opportunities, or create opportunities by their own, with the help of AI. So that here, in this area for mental well-being, we support fishners whose jobs are impacted by AI.
Sushma: And we increase the self-awareness, personal growth, and emotional well-being. So, use of AI to help, people grow and reach their potentials, not just to increase productivity. Here.
Sushma: This is our concept of A for mental well-being, and if I talk about the A for socioeconomic sustainability here, we enable the individuals to become independent professionals or entrepreneurs using AI.
Sushma: We tried, we're trying to collect…
Sushma: Trusted communities where people can, recognize their skills and contributions.
Sushma: So that, you know, we encourage people to develop specialized skills that create lasting value, instead of, you know, simply following the market trends.
Sushma: So, simply, if I talk about the FOG, FOG Impact Collaborative, so we believe that AI should improve people's lives.
Sushma: Not replace them.
Sushma: We work to ensure AI is fair, supports mental well-being.
Sushma: Create sustainable career opportunities, so that, you know, it can help and build a better future.
Sushma: For everyone. This is, like, you know, it's a non-profit organization.
Sushma: And it's a, you know, we are looking to collaborate with Oh…
Sushma: With everyone who were working towards the air for good.
Sushma: This is the… and also, in part of that, next month, mostly, like, you know, we are launching the essay contest, and in this essay contest.
Sushma: Our main thing is the future of AI, the future of AI economy, so that, you know, what are the new pro… just do a minute.
Sushma: So, in this essay contest, we can have, we can, you know, have the think tankers in our community, so from that, we can also, strengthen our community and do the, focusing all these, things.
Sushma: And if I talk about the role.
Sushma: HR interned. This role is having the
Sushma: two, primary role is HR, and second role is community building. So, all this primary role comes focusing into end-to-end HR operations.
Sushma: Including, recruitment to, like, the employee life cycle. If I say above that end-to-end HR operation means employee life cycle.
Sushma: So that, you will get a chance to explore and learn full employee lifecycle.
Sushma: And apart of that, you will get the exposure to Oh…
Sushma: work on AI, HR tools as well.
Sushma: And also, you know, and enhance that as well, and also the, what are the initiatives or required? You need to be work on that.
Sushma: And setting the culture, enhancing that, is also a part of that.
Sushma: And… Coming to the secondary role, community building.
Sushma: here I said that, we do have a community, so when I talk about the NG1 nonprofit organization, most of NGOs and non-profit organizations.
Sushma: We'll maintain a community, so that from that community, they can do an impact, work.
Sushma: So, we do have a community in Foji.
Sushma: And even in warm, So… As a… as a community, secondary role in community building.
Sushma: There are three focus things in community building. Inner circle, middle circle, and the outer circuit.
Sushma: So, the inner circle will be, like, you know, samples, which means interns and,
Sushma: Tankers will be there, and middle circle, partnerships, collaborators will be there.
Sushma: And outer circle, people at the large will be there. So, as a HRS, your second role will be, like, you know, engaging and motivating with the inner circle of community.
Sushma: So ensuring that, developing the various engagement initiatives
Sushma: And ensure that… stay connected with the community, and feel the commun… and so that the community can feel that. They also stay connected with the organization.
Sushma: what are the purpose that they are onboarded, like, you know, added in the think tankers. So, make sure that whether the purpose is filling or not from that community, and are the community members engaging and motivating.
Sushma: To do the impactful work that which they're, you know, onboarded in that community.
Sushma: So, this is a brief about us.
Sushma: And about the role.
Sushma: And it's a 6 months of internship tenure.
Sushma: And, yes.
Sushma: I just want, if anyone having any doubts, you can, you know, put on your questions, or otherwise, give me 5 minutes, I will come up with the result.
Bhumika K: So, Maya had a question. So all these,
Riya: 3, or…
Bhumika K: communities that you mentioned, inner circle, outer circle, middle circle, is that what you call a… call a sunker, Sankar, or whatever, that…
Bhumika K: It was given?
Sushma: Sankar says, like, you know, we don't want to call interns at
Sushma: interns, so we… for all the interns, we name them sankers. Okay. Not only the interns, like, you know, after, completing, who would like to, you know, continue as a consultant role, so everyone we call as a sample. The people, like, you know, employees, interns, everyone, we call them a.
Riya: Nope.
Riya: My headphones.
Riya: I have a mantel that is, in the JD, I have shown,
Sowmiya K R: The first two months of internship, we're going to third and fourth months, we have a result, and we have a performance rating. You need to have 4 out of 5. And what… how are we going to measure this performance?
Sushma: I will talk about that in the next turn, but if… now you're asking me, let me…
Sushma: It's… let me answer to that.
Sushma: See, the other thing is that, every 2 months, performance, cycle will be there, appraisal cycle will be there for 6 months of tenure. So, the people who completed first 2 months.
Sushma: their performance will be evaluated and, appraised for 3rd and 4th month. The people who completed three and four months
Sushma: will be evaluated and appraised for 4 and 6 months. So, for every appraisal, the two parameters will be there. The first parameter is the KRS of your… of the primary role and secondary role.
Sushma: and the performance… and the goals which is given to them, individual goals. So, based on their performance, it will be evaluated. And the second parameter is core values.
Sushma: We do have 5 core values in the organization, making sure that the values should be followed in day-to-day activities.
Sushma: So, based on average of these two, we give our rating.
Sushma: Out of 5.
Sushma: So, people who are getting food.
Sushma: people who are getting 4, they will… they will be getting a benchmark of amount. So, the stipend, whatever you're seeing in the job description, the first two months, 5K, third and fourth month, $7,500, 5th and 6th month, $10,000. These are the
Sushma: benchmark of amounts. If someone fulfilling the Patih hours per week, Every month.
Sushma: And if their rating is out of 5, above 4, for them only, there will be
Sushma: receiving the benchmark of these amounts. Instead of 30 hours, if they receive only 20 hours, if they invested 20 hours or 25 hours, then the amount will be created, the staffing amount will be created for those 20 and 25 hours which they invested. That's it.
Sushma: And the rating also, if out of 5, if they're rating less than 4, they cannot expect these benchmarks. It was clearly mentioned in the job description as well.
PEARL: Ma'am, supposedly, if a candidate fulfills only 5 to 10 hours, then the stipend will be deducted, right?
Sushma: It's not a deducted. They will be receiving for those 10 to 11 hours of work only. The benchmark of amounts, what we keep in 5K, 7,510K, the people who achieve 30 hours.
Sushma: We are not deducting anything.
Sushma: We are just giving whatever they invested, that's it. In the job description, what we mentioned, the people who invested 30 hours for them, the people who invested 30 hours and whose rating is out of above 4, they will receive that benchmark.
Riddhi Agarwal: It's another…
Sushma: There's no deduction here.
Sushma: It's a lot.
PEARL: We said that, we said that.
Sushma: criteria.
Riya: Okay, I have a question. If someone's performance is really, really low in the past two months… Your voice is too low. I can't hear. Can you please check on that?
Riddhi Agarwal: Ma'am, I wanted to ask, to track these 30 hours of performance, will we have to submit timesheets?
Sushma: We do have a Clockify tool, you will get access for that.
sneha : Ma'am, is there any alternative of full-time role after completing this successful internship?
Sushma: People who have successfully completed 6 months, and their performance is really up to the mark, and they're getting… and the values-wise also, they're up to the mark, they may chance of promoting into consulting.
Sushma: fellowship program is not rolled out. If the fellowship program is rolled out, they may get a chance of, having a fellowship program either 6 months or 12 months. After that, based on the funds, they may chance of getting the full time.
Riya: Okay, guys, just view me.
Riya: Sorry?
Riya: If the performance is really low in the first two months, is it possible for the internship to be terminated?
Riya: acknowledge.
Sushma: The…
Riya: If…
Sushma: The people are calling red, like, you know, at least 2.
Sushma: There will be tenants, yes.
Sushma: Not terminated immediately, we will provide them, we will understand.
Sushma: The challenges, we will understand their blockers, they will… we will understand their dedication availability.
Sushma: If that is not working, after multiple, attempts, the reservation will be… termination will be.
Sushma: Or otherwise, we will, we will, if they want to, continue with us, instead of that role, we will ask them to explore another role.
Sushma: To check on that.
Swetcha: How many positions need to be filled for the role of HR interns?
Sushma: Only one.
Sushma: benato.
Swetcha: Okay.
yashna: Ma'am, I was asking that you said that, it… there are, like, 5K is the benchmark for the first 2 months. So, like, someone is not, doing 30 hours per week, so they will not get any stipend, or,
yashna: Waterstone?
Sushma: It's not like that.
Sushma: If you, instead of 30 hours, you just invested 15 hours, you will get that 15 hours amount on it, not 30 hours or benchmark of that 5K.
yashna: Got it.
Sushma: Alright, completed.
Sushma: Can you please give me 5 minutes of time?
sneha : Mama, one more Disha.
sneha : How will be the performance evaluated during my internship?
Sushma: I already answered that.
Shivaansh: Sushma has joined the breakout room, no?
Sushma: Oh, you joined? When did you join?
Shivaansh: I joined, 5 minutes back.
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: Then… Okay, let's join the…
ashi: Ma'am, many of our Zoom chat box may drop Nig hour.
ashi: So, important here, Rakuten now.
Sushma: So… Now, I will be calling out a few names.
Sushma: The people who, like, I'm calling out, we appreciate your time and interest, but we are not going forward with the next round. You can leave the meet when your name was…
Sushma: like, you know, your name, which is called BuyMe.
Sushma: Riddhi, Suhani, Disha?
Sushma: Riya?
Sushma: Lubna?
Sushma: Oliva?
Sushma: Sujeta?
Sushma: Amit? Ananya?
Sushma: anam?
Sushma: Sneha?
Sushma: Pardon?
Sushma: ashi? Sakshit Gupta?
Sushma: Anish… Anisha, but…
Sushma: Am I clear?
Sushma: Can I repeat the names again?
Sushma: So, please leave the meat,
Sushma: Riddhi? Suhani Disha?
Sushma: Please leave the meat.
Sushma: Riya Lubna Oliva, Sujeta, Amit?
Sushma: Ananya?
Sushma: anam sneha PEARL
Sushma: Ashish, Sarkshi, Anisha, we appreciate your time and interest, but we are not going forward with the next hour. You people can leave this, mate.
Sushma: Thank you, have a nice day. Am I audible to everyone?
Sushma: I have seen.
Swetcha: Could you please clarify if you meant Sujitha or Swetcha?
Sushma: Sujitha.
Swetcha: Damn.
Sushma: Sujitha, yes.
Sujitha S: Yeah, it's myself.
Sujitha S: Thank you.
Sushma: Sneha?
Sushma: Patil as well.
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: people who was, who stayed here, I hope everyone dropped your resumes. If you didn't drop your resume, because I have seen few people I couldn't, you know, see in the resume, please drop it quickly.
Sushma: No.
Sushma: And now the discussion is, the same question to everyone.
Sushma: Please chat.
Sushma: These four questions, one after one. The first one is, what's your career goal? Why HR, and why FOG?
Sushma: What motivates you to do this internship?
Ranjana Sharma: Moon, can I go first?
Sushma: And also, please highlight if your psychology background does, please let us know as well.
Nitish chaudhary: Hi, please, could you repeat the questions?
Sushma: Yeah, I… I will. So, what's your career goal?
Sushma: YHR, YA4J, What motivates you to do this internship?
Sushma: And if you're from psychology background also, please highlight that. That's it.
Ranjana Sharma: Okay, ma'am, so can I go first?
Sushma: Yep.
Ranjana Sharma: Yeah, so, hi ma'am, good afternoon. Actually, the very first question, why HR, is because I previously did an internship from BSP, that is Bhai Steel Plant, in HR, and I got interest in HR, so that's why I,
Ranjana Sharma: want to do my internship in HR, and the second question is why, Anisha Foundation is, because previously I worked with one of the foundations, that is Shiva Foundation, and I worked here as a teaching intern, so I just want to…
Ranjana Sharma: work with another foundation, that is Anisha Foundation, so that's the reason. And, what motivates me for HR is because,
Ranjana Sharma: Yeah, I just want to learn how to manage people, because people, as I know, people is the most important asset of an organization. So I just want to know how to responsibilities.
Sowmiya K R: Same.
Nitish chaudhary: Hi, Shaheen, everyone. I would like to…
Sushma: Did you answer all the core questions?
Ranjana Sharma: Ma'am, why HR? My interest in HR on…
Ranjana Sharma: Yeah, because, in today's generation, AI is very important.
Ranjana Sharma: Yeah, I want to, I want a stable career in HR, that is human resource, and plus, I am preparing for UGCNet as well, so HR is the most important topic in UGCNet as well, so I just want to learn more about HR.
Sushma: Okay, next.
Nitish chaudhary: My agenda was one.
Nitish chaudhary: I'd like to start, from my background. I have turned my BTAC in computer science and engineering.
Nitish chaudhary: I always wanted to become a naval aviator, and in my first attempt, I cleared my SSP. I cleared my CPSS examination, but due to medical condition, I was not able to join the Naval Academy.
Nitish chaudhary: So I thought that, why not pivot my career, to the management? Because the learnings that I got from my SSP journeys, and also being serving as an academic counselor at Rafigarah Hill University, I want to pivot all the learnings into the human resource.
Nitish chaudhary: That is why…
Nitish chaudhary: I want to do, first of all, my career goal is to pivot, my background into MBA.
Nitish chaudhary: into human resource and finance platform. Along with that, I would like to answer why AFOG? Because my background is from artificial intelligence and machine learning. I know how to use the artificial intelligence ethically, so I've also… I think I can contribute more to this role as a computer science engineer.
Nitish chaudhary: And what motivates me to go for this role is that, first of all, I want to gain some experience. I want to learn, first of all, first-hand management. That's the same I would have been doing in the Indian Navy or the Indian Army.
Nitish chaudhary: So I'm going to pivot that into the human resource, and that is what motivates me to go for this opportunity. So thank you, Jahin.
Shrobana Sarkar: Ma'am, can I go next?
Sowmiya K R: No, thanks.
Sowmiya K R: Thank you for this opportunity, I'm Sowiya. First of all, my career course, I have a broader career course in two aspects. One is, I want to be a CPA people officer. That's my first preference, and another preference, I want to build a platform for those HR and the students. Like, if this platform is about, it gives the students what to do for the kids.
Sowmiya K R: area, and it provides, what kind of skills you can learn from this education. This will boost them to match with the perfect HR. So, I need to build the gap between the students and that HR through that platform. So, that's my career goal.
Sowmiya K R: that, actually, because I'm also coming from a MBA with AI and ML platform, which is integrated with my MBA also. So I think A4J could be the better option, because I know how ethical consideration and cybercrime survey developer in India so much, so I need to contribute something for people to understand.
Sowmiya K R: You know, if we… if we train the youth generation in a well-behaviour manner, we're gonna retain them.
Sowmiya K R: That's a… that's an invite.
Sowmiya K R: So, under my HR goals, that is a quite interesting story for me, because I have done English literature, where we say every nobles has a different story, it's a different aspect, different characters, they can handle the situation differently. So that motivates me to do human resource. Like, how actually people this? What in the reality would be? So that made me to do human resource.
Sowmiya K R: And what made me to do these internships, because we all know, as students, the time management would be the bigger crisis for us. So, 30 hours a week, so I can be able to focus more, because in my college, I have our flexi lunch, so I can have more time. So this 30 hours is a perfect timing for me. Instead of going completely towards the internships, this part-time internship, we're able to get
Sowmiya K R: more knowledge for me from the academic perspectives, and also from the internship perspective. So that's why I chose this. And A4G is a better platform for me, because I know how… how this came.
Sowmiya K R: play changes. For example, I need to quote something, means, in the UK past week, they have
Sowmiya K R: you know, they have stopped HRs to use the AI platforms to recruit the humans. That's the complete humans policy they have been created, and I have also done a case study related to it. So, as a HR, I know how…
Sowmiya K R: this AI will play a bigger role. So that's made me to choose A4G to build a more ethical AICS.
Shrobana Sarkar: Ma'am, first I want to, introduce my…
Shrobana Sarkar: some backstores.
Shrobana Sarkar: Here, my… Yes, you know, Singh from Vaidihi Medical College, I have done master's in college.
Sushma: Kalya, please check your bandwidth. Your voice is not much clear.
Shrobana Sarkar: Okay.
Shrobana Sarkar: Am I audible?
Shrobana Sarkar: Now, clearly.
Sushma: Yeah.
Shrobana Sarkar: Yes, first I would like to introduce myself. Myself, Shrobana Sarkar. I have done BSc Nursing from Vaidihi Medical College from Bangalore. After completion of my BS in Nursing, I have done Master's in Healthcare Management.
Shrobana Sarkar: from Jain University, Bangalore. So, I have done internship under Operations Department at Esther Hospital Bangalore, and I have nearly one year of work experience at Manipal Hospital under Operations Department, where I was supervising.
Shrobana Sarkar: And I was doing the interdepartmental communications and coordinations with surgeons, doctors, and everyone. So, yes, right now, I was… I'm doing the internship as an HR at Basket Han Private Limited, company.
Shrobana Sarkar: So, yes, my career objective is to build a strong foundation in human resource by gaining practical experience in recruitment, HR operations, as well as employee engagement. So, in the next 5 years, I… so that I can see myself as an HR professional.
Shrobana Sarkar: And why HR? I would like to tell that I am here because I want to learn, grow, and as well as build a successful career in HR. So, what drives me is the opportunity to work with people, solve problems, as well as,
Shrobana Sarkar: Take on, new challenges, and make a meaningful, like, contributions, and, like, and also the organization while continuously improving my skills.
Shrobana Sarkar: And if you ask me why FOG, because I would like to tell AFOG because your mission is the meaningful, completely. You use AI to solve real-world problems while focusing on ethics and sustainability, and I also like your collaborative culture.
Shrobana Sarkar: Like, I also believe that this internship will help me to develop my HR skills, as well as contribute to recruitment and people management, so, and to grow also in a, like, purpose-driven organization.
Shrobana Sarkar: So, yes, what,
Shrobana Sarkar: you asked me what motivates me. Like, yes, I am passionate about building a career in human resources. That's why I have left my job, and I have started doing my internship in HR. So, yes, I want to gain practical experience in recruitment, HR operations, and employee engagement. This opportunity offers me a, like, I would say, a structured learning
Shrobana Sarkar: environment where I can develop my skills.
Shrobana Sarkar: Thank you, ma'am.
Bhumika K: Mom, can I go next?
yashna: CET.
yashna: I would like to first introduce myself. My name is Yashna, and currently I'm pursuing my MBA in HR, and my career objective is to build a strong career in HRBP, or talent acquisition. HRP is such as, like, human resource and business partner. So, recently I've completed my internship at Taj Hotels in Chandigarh.
yashna: where it was, like, about 4-6 weeks, where I've gained hands-on experience on, like, employee engagement, onboarding, recruitment support, and all the documentation work. So that's why I have, like… I always had interest in this field, but during my internship tenure, I…
yashna: developed a keen interest, because it's, like, a people-centric, job, so I have to, like, I want to upskill myself, and, why A4G? Because, like, I think it's an organization which focuses on people and purpose, and also it, focuses on AI-enabled HR practices, and I believe this,
yashna: combination would, really enhance my, career in HR, and,
yashna: I want to, like, have a good, internship experience, because
yashna: during my, internship at, hotel industry, it was mainly, like, people-centric, and, I didn't have, like, more, payroll, experience, how to make payroll, because, like, they outsource the payroll,
yashna: the thing, and so I don't have, I don't know how to make, like, payroll and all, and I do want to, enhance these technical skills during this internship, that's why I want to, opt for this internship.
yashna: Thank you.
Bhumika K: Mom, can I go next?
Garima: Good evening, everyone. Myself, Garima Pande, and I am of…
Sushma: permissions, no need to ask the permissions. Please, you know, start one after one.
Garima: Good evening, everyone. My name is Kilma Pandey. I am currently pursuing
Garima: Bachelor's of Commerce, and I'm in my final year. Recently, I have completed my internship at Young Skin India, which is, situated in, Varanasi, Uttar Pradesh. During my internship at, Young Skin India, I worked closely with the HR and recruitment process. My responsibilities, included sourcing potential candidates, reaching out to students.
Garima: explaining internship opportunities, screening interested candidates, scheduling interviews, following up with applicants, and maintaining communication throughout the recruitment process. This experience improved my communication
Garima: Recruitment, coordination, and interpersonal skills, and strengthened my interest in pursuing a career in
Garima: human resource, and if you ask me that, what is my, career goal? So, my short-term goal is to gain, practical
Garima: experience in human resources, improve my skills in recruitment, employee engagement, and HR operations, and my long-term
Garima: Goal, is to become a skilled HR professional and eventually grow into a HR manager or HR business partner, where I can contribute to building a positive, workplace
Garima: Culture and support both employees and the organization.
Bhumika K: growth.
Garima: My, motivation for this internship, is to gain practical, experience in human resource and apply what I have learned during my, bachelor's, studies
Garima: I want to develop, my skills in recruitment and all the HR operations. I believe Omisha Foundation will provide me with a
Garima: Learning-oriented environment.
Sushma: Please keep it short and crispy. Please don't mind, because the rest of browns also will be there.
Sushma: It'll be Lindy, so please make an email.
Garima: HR operations, I believe Omisha Foundation will, provide me with learning-oriented environment where I can grow
Garima: professionally while contributing to meaningful social impact. I'm eager to learn from experienced professionals, take on new challenges, and build a strong foundation for my career.
Garima: why do I want to join, like, A4G? It's because, the mission is using artificial intelligence for social, good is, inspiring for me.
Garima: I'm interested in learning HR in an organization that values ethics, AI, teamwork, and continuous learning. I believe this internship will help me to
Garima: help me develop my HR skills while contributing to a meaningful mission. Thank you.
Bhumika K: Ma'am, I'm Bhumika, so I'm currently pursuing psychology. As you have mentioned, I have to mention if I'm from psychology background.
Bhumika K: So, why, my career goal is to become either an HRP or a learning and development professional. Because, from my previous internships and volunteering experience, I have done multiple aspects, like recruitment, onboarding, documentation, employee engagement. But then, in my volunteering experience, I had the opportunity to
Bhumika K: work one-on-one with an underprivileged student, where I had the chance to, you know, develop her and give career guidance to her. And then, I realized that I love developing people and seeing them grow into a successful person. So I thought I'll get into HR and then develop an entire, develop all the employees in the organization. So, if, that was my goal. So that is my career goal, to become a learning and
Bhumika K: development professional, or HRBP, and create a positive work culture.
Bhumika K: and to develop the employees constantly. And why A4G? You, as you mentioned previously, you work towards, you know, developing people, and then you're creating sustainable careers using AI. So, I believe this aligns with my career goals also, because I want to develop people professionally and personally. So I believe I can contribute meaningfully with my psychology background.
Bhumika K: Understanding people, and then being empathetic
Bhumika K: towards them, and using AI to, you know, develop them even more professionally. Why HR? As I mentioned before, HR is the main bridge in organization, and they understand people, they love to interact with people, they, ensure that employees' voices are heard, and also they ensure that they meet the employees' goals aligned with the organization's goals.
Bhumika K: I want to help in developing employees so that they can effectively contribute to the, the organization. Moving on to the last question, which you asked.
Bhumika K: What motivates you to apply for this internship? Well, previously, I have only had exposure mostly to recruitment and onboarding, and when I saw the JD, which stated that you can also enable people.
Sushma: Your voice is a little bit echoing. Can you please repeat?
Bhumika K: Can you please repeat? Is it not audible?
Bhumika K: Am I not audible? Can someone…
Swetcha: Fitching.
Sandy: Now you're audible.
Sushma: article.
Bhumika K: Come on.
Bhumika K: Was I not audible before?
Swetcha: Of course, yeah.
Sushma: I'm telling you, voice is a little bit cracking in between, so…
Bhumika K: Okay.
Bhumika K: Which part couldn't you hear, ma'am? So that I can, like, you know, read it?
Sushma: Last… last 30 seconds.
Bhumika K: Okay, so, as for, why I want, what motivates me to apply for this internship.
Bhumika K: I have previously worked in recruitment, onboarding, and employee engagement sort of internship, but it was mostly focused on recruitment, so I want to work in an organization which gives me the exposure to all forms of HR, not just, you know, recruitment. And when I saw the JD, that you also promote community building and, you know.
Bhumika K: Listen to employee grievance, listen to employee grievances, that is what we do. We listen to our clients' concerns in psychology. So, which align with my profession, and, align with the JD. That's why I applied to this role, because, it focuses on people development.
Swetcha: Alright, hi everyone, my name is Swetcha, and I am currently pursuing my honors in psychology, and
Swetcha: For my career goal, I would like to add that I am currently preparing for CAT 2027-28. So, I really want to pursue an MBA in HR.
Swetcha: And HR has always caught my interest, especially because I am someone who is a very people-centered person, and HR serves exactly that. HR is a very people-centered role, I believe. And the opportunity at A4G especially interests me, because it is combining not just
Swetcha: the AI aspect of what the company stands for. The company stands for AI for Good, but it is also centered somewhere about dealing with people in a way that they feel recognized, they feel important, and they feel they're making some sort of contribution. So.
Swetcha: When I reviewed the role, and when I reviewed everything, I just felt that it aligned perfectly with what I have been looking for the past few months.
Swetcha: And I have also worked as a proposal writer, so I have some experience in reviewing resumes and the process of recruitment that is, like, basic to every HR role. And I really like how I get to innovate in the role that A4G is providing.
Swetcha: So, this is what I have to add from my end. Thank you so much.
Sushma: What's your college timings?
Swetcha: My college timings are from 7am to 1pm.
Swetcha: However, my classes are pretty flexible. Sorry?
Sushma: I'm asking, Bhumika, thank you.
Bhumika K: Oh.
Sushma: Your voice is breaking for me.
Bhumika K: My college timings are from 9.30 to 12.30, and it's nearby, so…
Bhumika K: hello? Am I audible now, Ma?
Sushma: While you're asking, I mean, audible to you? It was audible to me, but while you're starting talking, it… your voice is breaking in between.
Bhumika K: Oh, okay, sorry for the… I think there's something wrong with the.
Sushma: Yeah, you can look into that. So, tell me your Polish times.
Bhumika K: It's from, 9.30 to 12.30.
Sushma: Alright, go ahead, next person.
Ranjana Sharma: My college timing is from 9 to 2. 9am to 2pm.
Sushma: Alright, alright.
Sushma: Okay, next person, please go ahead.
Sushma: Thank you.
Eshita Singh: Hello everyone, I'm Eshita. So, let's start with my academic
Eshita Singh: academics, that, I started, my graduation in BSc, then I did, BEd, and, in BEd, I learned about the student psychology, more about in certain subjects in that.
Eshita Singh: And then I pursued my MBA, wherein MBA… while pursuing my MBA, I recognized that HR fits me, and the behavior I have, and
Eshita Singh: the behavior that HR should have is aligning to it. So I choose HR because I enjoy working with people and helping organizations.
Eshita Singh: Building strong teamwork.
Eshita Singh: And, throughout my MBA journey, I moreover realized this
Eshita Singh: And, in that order, I pursued many internships. Some were marketing internships and HR internships, but later on, I realized that HR suits me more, because marketing was not my,
Eshita Singh: goal, and I realized that whatever the HR work that was asked in the internship fascinates me, and I enjoy doing that work.
Eshita Singh: And why this organization? Because throughout that internship journey, I miserably look after the roles like recruitment, sourcing.
Eshita Singh: and onboarding. But here in this internship, there is other aspects of HR that probably I'm going to cover. For example, Grivian's herding, and how
Eshita Singh: And how in-house employers work, and how that policy…
Sushma: Please, please be on pawn. What I ask, those four questions, answer for those questions only. Please, don't, you know, elaborate, just keep short and concise.
Eshita Singh: Okay.
Eshita Singh: Okay, okay. So, hence I want my HR… HR as my career in future, and I want to be a super good HR executive in future, and working in very good organization. So, this is crisp, as you asked me, so thank you for it.
Sushma: All right, thank you. And Bhumika, I couldn't be able to open your resume. Can you please look into that and reshare that rest, you know, PDF?
Bhumika K: Oh, yes.
Sushma: So I'm wondering.
Bhumika K: Yes, I'll, give…
Sushma: And also, Eshita, could you please drop your resume? I didn't receive that.
Eshita Singh: Yes, ma'am.
Sushma: Completed, everyone?
Sushma: Yes, we are done, right?
Sushma: holiday.
Sushma: It just, let's go to the breakout room, like, Sandy and, sandy and Shivansh.
Sandy: Yes.
Bhumika K: Ma'am, am I audible now?
Sushma: Yeah, you're right.
Bhumika K: I submitted my CV, can you try downloading it?
Sushma: Yeah, yeah.
Sushma: Yeah, I can see that.
Sushma: Yeah, thank you.
Sandy: Sushma, can you assign me?
Sushma: Oh, okay, okay, okay, I'm doing that.
Sushma: Let me do the co-hosts.
Sushma: Oh, I couldn't see it.
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: Guys, please hold on. Three…
Sushma: 3 to 4 minutes, we will be back with the results.
Sushma: And we'll let you know who… who we are going… with whom you are going to affect.
Sushma: Nope.
Sushma: Right, I didn't receive Sowmia's resume and Eshita. Did you drop your resume? Can you please give it?
Eshita Singh: Yes, ma'am, I do.
Sushma: Should I interviewed now.
Sushma: Sowmiya, could you please drop it quickly?
Sowmiya K R: Yeah, well, my dad…
Sowmiya K R: Durga.
Sushma: Judy, thank you, thank you.
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: Shrobana?
Sushma: Nitish Kumar?
Sushma: Garima?
Sushma: Sorry, Nitish Kumar Chaudhary.
Sushma: Ranjana, four of you, we appreciate your time and interest, but we are not moving forward with the next round. All the best for your future. Have a nice day.
Sushma: Garima, you can also leave. Thank you.
Sushma: I think 5 out there, right?
Sushma: Perfect. Okay. So guys, thereafter, rounds will be one-to-one, HR round, nature fitment, organizational fitment rounds will be there.
Sushma: So… The people who are sharing in the breakout room.
Sushma: Please, you know, wait for some time.
Sushma: When your turn comes.
Sushma: You will be assigned in the main session. So, in the breakout room, you can turn off your video, and you can do some of the work, and when you assign in the main session, you must be turned on video and do the rest of your apps.
Sushma: Cleo?
Sushma: And, like, you know, please, you know, we just planned, all should be taken in the same day.
Sushma: So, maybe if it is getting delayed, please wait patiently.
Sushma: And cooperate with us.
Sushma: Hello.
Sushma: Please join everyone who got the room to join, except Kumika.
Sushma: Hi Bhumika, so you said that your college timings is up to 2, right?
Bhumika K: No, ma'am, it's still 12.30. Am I audible?
Sushma: Yeah, yeah, you're out of it.
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: So, tell me your last bronze stipend.
Bhumika K: My last internship stipend?
Sushma: Yes, yes, yes.
Bhumika K: It was 10K.
Sushma: 10K per month?
Bhumika K: Yes, ma'am. But, it's negotiable, because I'm more into growing and learning these days, so…
Bhumika K: I'm fine with, a people-oriented internship.
Sushma: Okay. See, this… I already explained about the stipend structure in the first round itself. Do you have any questions and concerns in that?
Bhumika K: No, ma'am, as of right now, I understand that it's based on performance and also the hours that you work for, so there's not an issue with that.
Sushma: It should not be beyond 10K, so past 2 months, 5K, next 7,500, next 10K.
Bhumika K: It's…
Sushma: Again, if you're inverse 30 hours and if you're rating before, you can expect that kind of set.
Bhumika K: Yes, no, that won't be a problem.
Sushma: Okay. Do you have any offers or interviews in pipeline?
Bhumika K: Yes, ma'am, I did do interviews, but I mean, I have submitted my profiles to other internship also, like, on-site also I've submitted, but then I didn't receive any response from them.
Bhumika K: And then, one more was there, but, they told, their, they have closed the job as of right now. I asked them to wait for a few more weeks, because I was doing an internship at that time. Till now, I have, this week for this internship to complete.
Bhumika K: So, yeah, I'll have, like, I have, like, 3-4 days left for this internship. So, they didn't wait for me, so I don't have any other offers as of right now.
Sushma: Okay, the present internship, what's the timing of the present internship, which is going to complete this week, right?
Bhumika K: Yes, ma'am. It, is from 9 to 6. It's a full… it's a full-time job kind of a role. So, it's like 9 to 6. Afterwards, in August, my college is starting, so I can work from 3 to 9, that's not an issue.
Sushma: Okay. Do you have any other commitments, like online or offline courses, or any freelancing, or any other internships?
Bhumika K: No, ma'am, I do ha- I do volunteer on… yes, ma'am, on Saturdays and Sundays.
Bhumika K: I volunteer, but that's for 2 hours. Saturdays, I don't have college. So, in the morning, I have volunteering, which is from 9 to 11. Again, it won't affect or overlap with this internship.
Bhumika K: And then on Sundays also, it's from, Sundays, we don't have work… a working day anyway, so it's from, 9 to, 1, I have another volunteering work. So, it doesn't overlap, ma'am. Most of my commitments doesn't overlap with this internship.
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: Chill, going to complete your bachelor's in the year of 2027.
Bhumika K: Yes.
Sushma: Luna July, okay. Silvania would be good.
Sushma: Tell me how will your career aspiration will be aligned to this internship or to this organization?
Bhumika K: Ma'am, as I mentioned in the previous round, I'm, planning to pursue organizational psychology in the future. So, this, internship is all about people and development, developing employees.
Bhumika K: So, I believe this internship would contribute a lot to my understanding of people management, you know, people development, and, you know, practically engaging in them would give me practical exposure to that aspect also. And I love working with people and developing them, because I recently realized that I would work well in a role where I would develop employees or develop people, so…
Bhumika K: If I'm, satisfied with one person being, developed.
Bhumika K: I think I would, it would be more rewarding if I'm developing multiple people at the same time. So, that is why I applied for this internship, and also, you have mentioned that you're trying to create a sustainable career for people who cannot,
Bhumika K: you know, get jobs as such, in A4G. So, I believe, I can work towards it, because I love developing people. I have also trained, one individual during one of my volunteering activity.
Bhumika K: So, I guess, this way I can develop people and also help, provide psychological support also, because I have a background in psychology, so I can develop them personally and professionally and mentally also.
Sushma: Perfect.
Sushma: What they're expecting from this internship?
Bhumika K: Ma'am, I hope I can learn a lot, because I, recently realized, because in my previous internship, recruitment is, just, you know, the same repetitive tasks.
Bhumika K: So I believe it's more than recruitment in this internship. So I believe I can learn about… more about onboarding, employee engagement, you know, engaging in, engaging communities, as y'all mentioned, the three inner circle, three inner circles.
Bhumika K: hope I can engage them, and I hope I can conduct training sessions. I hope I can contribute a lot, so I think I want to, you know, use my psychology background to train people, and then give extra sessions
Bhumika K: on coaching, I could… I hope I can do a lot, like, those aspects also.
Bhumika K: I can give insights about psychology, and I can even try career development plans, or I can… because I have done that in my volunteering activities, so I guess I can… I'm experienced in that also, so I can do that also in this case.
Sushma: Okay, so are you comfortable to commit to 6 months if you got shortlisted?
Bhumika K: Yes, ma'am, that's not an issue, because I can manage… I have managed previously also, I have done an online internship also. At that time, I have managed both my college, volunteering activities and internships, so that won't be an issue for me.
Sushma: 10 years of that intention?
Bhumika K: It was also 6 months. The online internship, it was for 6 to 7 months, so I can manage pretty well.
Sushma: Tell me your family background, what do your father, mother do, and siblings? And where are you from?
Bhumika K: Ma'am, I'm from Trivedi. I was born in Trivedi, but I was brought up completely in Bangalore. From schooling till, I mean, till college, I have been in Bangalore, so I can say I'm a Bangalorean by heart.
Bhumika K: So, apart from that, my father is currently… he's working as a senior sales manager in one of the startup companies.
Bhumika K: And, he works for under IBM also. He sells IBM products. And my mom is a housewife, and my sister recently completed her bachelor's, and she's actively looking for jobs. She recently finished her graduation, and she's looking for jobs. That is my background.
Sushma: Alright, so any questions that you would like to ask us?
Bhumika K: Ma'am, what kind of, opportunities would you provide in this internship? I want to know, in a detailed manner, so that I can understand…
Sushma: You just mentioned that organizational psychology, so you will get… so these organizations where you will be getting a chance to, like, you know, if I know that people who are demotivated.
Sushma: Okay? Just graced. Not up to… the engagement is not up to the mark. So, you know, finding them, chatting with them, finding the root cause, and coming with some initiatives also, you will get a chance to, you know, have that kind of, exposure here.
Sushma: So, end-to-end HR operations will be there in the primary role, and whereas here in the HR, in the CB also, you are dealing with the people.
Sushma: You'll be dealing with the people's, behavior, engagement, motivation.
Sushma: And ensuring them to stay connected, with the work, like, you know, these anchors, like, other.
Sushma: And then the community, the target community. So, mostly, it will be applied directly aligned to your, like, you know, psychology study. So, whatever you learn, so maybe there is a chance to, you know, have a practical exposure here, whatever you're studying technical.
Sushma: I can say this.
Bhumika K: Another question, I want to ask, ma'am. So, in my previous internship, I had, like, an account in my current internship that I'm going to finish this week.
Bhumika K: So, I have, like, a Razor Pay account. Would that manage… that would manage attendance, and even the payment as such. So, is there any platform that you'll be using?
Bhumika K: See, I can manage older.
Sushma: Rakuten.
Bhumika K: Ranger.
Sushma: admins tracking, actually, we have the HRMS.
Sushma: Soft.
Bhumika K: Hmm?
Sushma: But, you know, currently it is not active, because we are, we are looking into…
Bhumika K: AI tools as well.
Sushma: So, me gladly are, like, So, there is an, like, we are, tracking from Google Sheet itself.
Bhumika K: Okay.
Sushma: But we do have a, recruitment tool.
Bhumika K: Hmm?
Sushma: And also the assessment tool as well. And, also we are trying to also build some few HR automation tools.
Sushma: That, you know, you will get a chance to collaborate with tech team for that development.
Bhumika K: Nope.
Sushma: automation tools, HR automation tools.
Bhumika K: Final question, ma'am, so would we also have the chance to interact with, some of the leadership team as such in, A4G? Because they all have, done exceptional work, so I would also love to, you know, interact.
Sushma: Yeah, operational leaders, the, like, you know, as of now, the two operational leaders are there. So, most of our interactions will be operational leaders, because.
Bhumika K: Oh my god.
Sushma: Team meetings, they will be going to go in to interact with the interns and giving the conceptual understanding.
Bhumika K: In the world.
Sushma: So, you will get a lot of, like, you will get a chance, every day, like, you know, a chance to talk with the founder as well, which is one of our operational leaders. So, you will get most of insight from him as well.
Bhumika K: Okay, so if I do get shortlisted, what is the duration? Like, when would I receive all the details and all those aspects?
Sushma: Hmm.
Sushma: Sorry, come again?
Bhumika K: If, was I not audible, ma'am?
Sushma: Come, I missed your question, sorry.
Bhumika K: So, if I do get shortlisted, what is the duration, that I can expect all the details regarding the internship?
Sushma: See, now, like, you know, your natural rate treatment and your organizational treatment round will be taken by Sandy.
Sushma: Where, like, you know, we, we need, we,
Sushma: We must, like, we almost, will take time one day to evaluate.
Bhumika K: There, oh.
Sushma: you got shortlisted, you will, you will hear from us for the further step. There is another step, is that, for the secondary roles, you've been extracted equipment, or, like, you know, we will look into
Sushma: And also, operational leaders. With operational leader, one last round will be there. So, if you got your.
Bhumika K: Okay.
Sushma: in this lab, so that you will get a chance to interact that. Mostly.
Sushma: Like, end of the… if you got shortlisted, you will hear from us within 2-3 days.
Bhumika K: Okay.
Sushma: If you didn't hear from us, you know, you can consider that we just moved with someone else, that's it.
Bhumika K: Okay. So, basically, there are 2 more rounds left, right?
Sushma: Two more rounds means, now the HR and HR department will be taken, and secondary role, which is, you know, CB or some other thing, so we have to look into that later, and OEL round also will be there.
Bhumika K: Oak.
Sushma: Okay.
Bhumika K: That's it from my side, Ma. Thank you.
Sushma: Yeah, alright.
Sushma: Thank you. So, over to you, Sandy.
Sandy: Hi, Bhumika.
Sandy: I hope I'm ordering you. Hi, Sandy.
Bhumika K: Yeah, you're audible. Am I audible?
Sandy: Yeah, yeah, you're audible.
Sandy: So, I'm starting with the questions, alright?
Sandy: Suppose an employee comes to you upset about not being promoted.
Sandy: Feel overlooked and demotivated.
Sandy: How would you handle the situation?
Bhumika K: Okay, so first I would try to understand, them, and try to, you know, give them few, pointers, like.
Bhumika K: I would try to, be empathetic towards them, try to understand from their point of view. Then try not to be, you know, take… I'll try not to take sides as such. I'll try to be neutral.
Bhumika K: And then, I should not also be, misleading or, I should not be, like, taking side of the management or the employee. So I'll try to be neutral, and then maybe offer her a third perspective.
Bhumika K: like, maybe, the management, didn't have the time to, you know, see you or recognize you, and then maybe I would, address her concerns, and then after that, I would give her a different perspective. After giving her a different perspective.
Bhumika K: If she still feels that she's not being recognized, or if she still feels, you know, if she still feels demotivated by the organization, maybe I'll talk to one of her managers, or her supervisor.
Bhumika K: I would enlist all the things that she has done, and I would try to tell them that she's feeling disengaged, and she does her work, and maybe I'll try to collaborate with them, and then make sure that she feels appreciated. And then, in a remote setting, in this case.
Bhumika K: if she has achieved something recently, maybe conduct a meeting, and then, I mean, recognize all the employees who have done exceptional work, and in this case, if she has done it, I would also appreciate her, and along with the manager.
Sandy: Oak.
Sandy: Just one suggestion, I would prefer it if you kept the answer to the point and crisp.
Sandy: If that's true.
Bhumika K: Oh, yeah.
Sandy: A manager complains that employees are confused about a new HR policy you introduced.
Sandy: How do you explain?
Bhumika K: You too.
Bhumika K: First, I think I would conduct a survey. I would ensure that which aspect of the policy is confusing to them. Then, maybe I would conduct a training session on what the actual policy is. Maybe the step-by-step training, a step-by-step training would be more insightful for the employees, so that they'll understand what the policy is actually about.
Sandy: Alright.
Sandy: An employee is underperforming, but is highly popular with the team. How would you address this?
Bhumika K: So, first, we need to recognize whether the disengagement or demotivation is due to, you know, the environment.
Bhumika K: Or is it because they're not being recognized? Or is it because of the pay?
Bhumika K: Or is it because of their personal issues? First, we need to understand that, so we need to ask them, we need to sit with them, have a one-on-one session, and then ask them what is their, what, happened, why is, that you have been, not directly stated to them, but then tell them you're such an exceptional performer, but then why… what happened to your…
Bhumika K: Recently. Maybe then, with a Rapo building, few Rakut building session.
Bhumika K: And I could maybe retrieve the information from them, and then based on that, I could, you know, inform their manager or the team, the team lead, and then tell them this is what is happening with one of your employees. So maybe it would be better if they address it soon, because they're also popular, and if they were previously performing exceptionally, they wouldn't want to lose such an employee, right? So they have to retain such employee.
Bhumika K: So maybe work on that.
Sandy: Okay.
Sandy: Imagine you join a company where HR is only seen as administrative.
Sandy: How would you change that perception?
Bhumika K: Okay, so, first of all, we all think HR is just for recruitment, and most of the employees think it's for recruitment, and, you know, they appear during payroll time and all those things. So, in order to break off that, stigma, I would, probably, help in, you know, conducting engagement activities.
Bhumika K: And then checking in with the employees, because it matters a lot these days, as one of the HR trends these days is how to maintain employees' mental well-being. So, I would regularly check in with…
Bhumika K: with the employees. And then I would also try to, you know, provide them the opportunity to grow and develop, and then interact with the senior managers and the higher management leadership team also, because in that case, if they get guidance from them, they would also be highly engaged.
Bhumika K: So, in that way, I would also improve them in that aspect. And, apart from that, I would also, you know, address their grievance. I would identify whether they're satisfied or not, because after an engagement activity, I would conduct a survey and see if they still, you know.
Bhumika K: where to improve, I would receive regular feedbacks from them about the training session or employee engagement activity, so that they don't see them as just a manager who's there for hiring.
Bhumika K: someone or, you know, payroll, those kind of roles, or policy, payrolls. So, that is why I would try to, you know, regularly check in with them, conduct training session, employee engagement activities, development.
Bhumika K: So, and creating, maybe an employee resource group also, so that, they can form similar groups, with peop- they can form a group with people who have similar interests to them. So, that also I can initiate that also.
Bhumika K: So they won't see them as an administrative person.
Sandy: Okay.
Sandy: Now, I'll be starting with the organizational Fed questions. So, tell me about a time when you took responsibility for an outcome that was not.
Bhumika K: Into.
Sandy: It's entirely your fault. And what did you do that time?
Bhumika K: Okay, so recently in my internship, in my, I think it was my second month of the internship, at that time, the, what happened was, I was, the day that the interview was supposed to happen.
Bhumika K: I was the one who was coordinating the interviews. I felt sick. I couldn't get out of my bed. I had high fever. And at that time, nobody was informed on who's going to be conducting the interview. And I even asked the manager a few times on who's going to be conducting the interview. There was no clear communication from the supervisor side.
Bhumika K: So nobody knew the inter… the interviewers who were supposed to take the interview didn't know they were actually supposed to take the interview today.
Bhumika K: So, they were also confused. They didn't know who to contact. Then I realized that this was the issue, and one of the colleagues informed me about this issue. So, what happened was, I called the, I called my other manager and informed what happened, what, happened during the situation. And then I took accountability completely. I was, even, the, I even, apologized to the candidate, stating that it was.
Bhumika K: A miscommunication from my side.
Bhumika K: So, there was not a proper communication on who is going to be doing what, which led to this entire event taking place, but then I took accountability from my side, because I should also have, you know, probed more about who will be conducting what.
Bhumika K: So, after that, I ensured that all the interviews are happening on time, and who is conducting the interview, and the person is informed about it.
Sandy: Okay.
Sandy: If you strongly disagree with a teammate's idea, but they are senior to you, how would you respond?
Bhumika K: Maybe I'll try to see what the major… even though if I don't agree with them.
Bhumika K: Sometimes it's better to be objective, see their point of view also. Maybe a few pointers that I actually like from them by being objective, and then stating that I actually like that part of it, I would maybe appreciate them for that, and then I would say, you have opened a new perspective for me, and this helped me to, you know, think in a different way.
Bhumika K: So, that is how it should work. Rather than disagreeing, maybe see a point of view that you never thought about.
Bhumika K: So, you might have not thought about a certain situation in that aspect. So, maybe I'll take that into consideration, and maybe that would help me grow perspectives also.
Sandy: If you are stuck because a process is slowing you down, what would you do?
Bhumika K: I usually try to stay consistent, and I'm, what do, what I do is, even if I feel disengaged, or if I'm stuck.
Bhumika K: what I do is give me some, give myself some time. I see, I reflect on what went wrong, what is, to be done, what areas I should improve.
Bhumika K: So, whenever, if I, in my college, sometimes I don't feel like doing my assignments or, a study as such. At that time, I take some time, take few breaks, I engage in activities that I love to do.
Bhumika K: I engage in reading books or exercising, I do those kind of things, then I gain perspective. Then I'm like, okay, let's start off by breaking the tasks. Then I break down the tasks.
Bhumika K: into smaller bits. So, I do, like, I'll keep certain amount of time, allotted to that task. So this one hour per day, I'll allot for this task. Even though I'm stuck, I'll try to give my, best to that task. So, instead of doing all at once, I'll break down the tasks, and then, do the, try to finish the tasks.
Sandy: Okay.
Sandy: Have you ever suggested a new idea or approach at work?
Bhumika K: And then what happened?
Bhumika K: Could you repeat that question again?
Sandy: I said, have you ever suggested a new idea, or a new.
Sandy: at work.
Bhumika K: Okay.
Bhumika K: Yeah, recently, in, one of, my internships, I, helped, one of,
Bhumika K: I, helped one of the interns, in, using, helping her how to use, an Excel function. So she didn't use how, she didn't know how to use that before.
Bhumika K: But then I, assisted her that you can also use… she used it in a certain way.
Bhumika K: Like, she used, she used a different way to use that, function, but then I showed her a different way, and then she got to know about the existence of this method also. So, I helped her in recognizing a new way to use an Excel function.
Sandy: Okay. Thank you, Bhumika, that was all from my end.
Sandy: Sushma is good.
Sushma: Okay, see, so this interview process will take, like, you know, what I said, like, the rest of… we are having, like, you know, two more rounds. One is with organizations, Raja, and the one is your secondary loan, external development.
Sushma: So it usually takes 2 to 3 days, so after that, after completing your internship there, within 4 days of
Sushma: Okay, can we expect that you're a manager joiner, or do you have any other commitments? If you go.
Bhumika K: No, I'm an immediate joiner after that. There's no commitments. Apart from my college, which is only for 2-3 hours, I don't have any other commitments on weekdays.
Bhumika K: tenant, till Saturday.
Sushma: Yeah, that's it from our end. If you don't have any questions to ask, any, you know, concerns or queries, you can drop your contact number, email address in the chat box. We will get back to you.
Bhumika K: Yes.
Bhumika K: That's… I don't have any…
Bhumika K: Any questions, I'll just drop my number, and…
Sushma: Yeah, please do that.
Bhumika K: I dropped my contact details, can you check if your PC here?
Sushma: You can leave. Thanks. That's it for today's interview. Thanks for joining.
Bhumika K: Thank you.
Sandy: Yeah, I would say she is good, but then I would still look for a better candidate.
Sushma: Yeah, she's good, decent only. At least we need someone very immediately, you're probably a replacement of Shivaans, so…
Sushma: I can say that, both replacements, she's like, you know, okay, because we had to take one.
Sushma: And she's, above average, I can say that.
Sandy: Yeah, she has good experience also, I've seen her resume.
Sushma: Let's see.
Sushma: Bye, Suja.
Swetcha: Hi, Elon.
Sushma: Oh… What's your last, bronze stipend from your previous internship?
Swetcha: Actually, it was a full-time job, and I was earning $19,000 per month there.
Sushma: 19, 19K.
Swetcha: Who's not.
Sushma: Okay. Are you currently studying?
Swetcha: Yes, I'm a student right now.
Sushma: Okay, then how did you manage your full-time job along with your, with your, you know.
Sushma: for, economics.
Swetcha: Yeah, the thing is that the, job was actually based on night shift, so it was a US-based company. All the work was US-based, so the timings were from 4am to… sorry, I'm saying 4am, 4pm to, 12.
Swetcha: And at night. So, those timings did not really clash with my,
Sushma: 4pm to 12am.
Swetcha: Saudi?
Sushma: It's, like, your time is 4pm to 12am, right?
Swetcha: Right.
Swetcha: So it didn't really clash with my college timings directly, and during my exams and all, the CEO was very cooperative, and I had really good relations with my hiring managers, and it was a very deadline-based job, like, you had to reach your deadlines, so…
Sushma: As a composer writer, right?
Swetcha: Right.
Sushma: Okay, why did you lift your job?
Swetcha: It is just that it was,
Swetcha: starting to feel like that the job didn't really align with where I wanted to go with my career. I'm studying psychology, and even though I enjoy writing very much, writing is something that I'm very passionate about. After one point, that job stopped serving a learning curve to me. Like, I wasn't learning anything new, the tasks became repetitive.
Swetcha: So, I thought for my career growth, it is important to leave that job and gain some experience in a field where I am actually interested, and that is HR for me.
Sushma: Okay, what if the HR end-to-end operations is repetitive for you?
Swetcha: I believe HR is something that I actually want to do with my career, even if it becomes repetitive for me, I know that
Swetcha: HR is a people-centered role, and people never stay consistent, as we know. We get to know new more… we get to know new people, we get to interact, we get to make connections, so that is what I love about HR, and even if the
Swetcha: Patterns are consistent, the people you're dealing with never are.
Sushma: Do you want to set… do you want to start your career in HR, or any psychology-relevant roles that you're looking?
Swetcha: I'm very set in starting my career in either organizational psychology or HR.
Sushma: So, Swetcha here, the pay is not, you know, very near to your last run also, so what do you think about that? Do you have any separate expectations for this… for this internship stipend?
Swetcha: No, I don't have a problem, like, I…
Swetcha: clearly read what the pay will be for this internship, and I am pretty okay with starting with where you are giving me the stipend, because HR is something new to me, and I understand that, and I'm looking for experience here, so I am pretty alright with the pay that you are providing at Umyashaw.
Sushma: Okay, tell me how your career aspiration will be aligned to this internship.
Swetcha: As I have already told you, that I am pursuing my honours in psychology right now, and I'm also preparing for CAT, and I will be giving my CAD exam this year as well, and next year as well. This year, just for the experience, and I'm actually graduating next year.
Swetcha: And I want to complete my MBA centered around HR itself, and we also studied organizational psychology, particularly in our academic
Swetcha: coursework. So, that is something that… where I found that my peak… my interest peaked.
Swetcha: And that is why I am applying for an HR role.
Sushma: So, when you're planning to view your cat in the month of November, mostly, right?
Sushma: So, how you're going to manage, along with your academics and preparation for CAD and these internship commitments?
Swetcha: I actually have a full set plan for that. Even though I'm not giving a CAD very seriously this year, I'm just giving it for the experience. I actually want to crack the examination next year, because that is the year I'm actually graduating.
Swetcha: And I have been preparing for the examination for one year now, so it's not that I'm dedicating too much time to the preparation, I am…
Swetcha: managing my college, and I was still studying for CAD when I worked in my previous job. That should be, I think, something noteworthy. So, I believe I can manage that pretty nicely, and HR is something that directly aligns with CAD, like, when they're interviewing you for MBA.
Swetcha: And when I actually want to do an HR degree in MBA, I think this internship would be very useful to me there.
Sushma: Okay, so what you're expecting from this internship?
Swetcha: I mean, mainly what I must… sorry, I got a little nervous, but mainly what I am expecting from here is whatever you mentioned, like, as I said in the previous round also, I loved everything that the foundation was offering to me. It has a learning curve, it is associated with people directly, and you are giving
Swetcha: a space to…
Swetcha: Like, actually learn something, and to give our own contribution in a very personal way, like.
Swetcha: There is not ESSA.
Swetcha: We are also getting to learn within set standards, but we are also getting to give our creative solutions to the problems that HR faces. So, that is why Omisha Foundation was specifically very important for me to apply in, and that is all I have to say about that.
Sushma: Okay?
Sushma: So, like, are you willing to commit 6 months, next 6 months, for this intention? We got shortlisted?
Swetcha: Yes, I am.
Swetcha: I'm available for the next 6 months, and I'm available to join immediately as well.
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: I think, you don't have any much hands-on experience in HR, right?
Swetcha: Actually, as a proposal writer, I might not have…
Swetcha: direct experience with HR, but when I was writing proposals, so what proposal writing actually does is submit resumes for the companies you're working with to USGovcon. So, we were government contracting, so I might not have direct experience working with HR, but I understand how recruitment works, and how
Swetcha: Resumes are made, and… how ZoomMate are actually allocated to the position that we are filling in.
Sushma: Okay, alright. Tell me about your family background, what do you father, mother, and do, and where are you from?
Swetcha: I'm from Chandigarh, and my… both my parents work as shared brokers, and I also have an older sister, and she's a banker.
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: Any questions that you would like to ask me? Any thoughts or concerns, queries, clarification?
Swetcha: I just want, I just want to clarify that,
Swetcha: as an HR intern, what would you expect from me? Like, I understand the basic,
Swetcha: that you have listed, the basics you have listed, that HR interns are expected to do. But, it is very closely related to AI, I understand, so I would like to know how we are using AI for recruitment in this group role.
Sushma: Okay, as of now, we are not, like, you know, we are not depending the decision making.
Sushma: on AI. We are just, using the AI tools to sending the messages in bulk. After, you know, even the screening also we are doing manually, not we are depending upon AI at actual.
Sushma: So we do have a tool that once, you know, the shortlisted candidates will be uploaded.
Sushma: And sharing them, you know, Google Forms to Pill and interview links in bulk at a time.
Sushma: And so that we can save some time.
Sushma: And, a part of that, so all these interviews will be recorded, and, with Zoom AI transcript, we capture each and every vote.
Sushma: So, it will, you know, without any assumptions, with the help of transcript, AI will help, AI tool, there is another AI tool for recruitment. So, helps to evaluate that.
Sushma: help us, you know, even though… but we are not blindly following that AI suggestions and recommendations.
Sushma: Because VHS already taken the interview, we know that whether it captured correctly or not. So, we will do that internal adjustments, but just for supporting, we will, you know, refer back, recommendations by end as well.
Swetcha: Okay, so as someone who's already working in HR, what would be the main reason if I'm not recruited today? Like, what would be the main cause to that?
Sushma: I didn't get you coming in.
Swetcha: Like, what would be the main contributing factor, in case I'm not recruited today? As a niche, what are you exactly looking for?
Swetcha: that I might be missing for this role.
Sushma: Still, I didn't much understand. So, are you asking…
Sushma: Any feedback? Like, no, I didn't get…
Swetcha: feedback, only I would like…
Sushma: Yeah, yeah.
Swetcha: Do you want to proceed.
Sushma: Exactly, you're asking that? Okay. See, this is…
Swetcha: It's not who cares.
Sushma: No, it doesn't mean that, you know.
Sushma: See, I, I can see one, you, you are there from starting, when you joined at 3pm.
Sushma: And you've seen how many people joined there, from how many people you just, you know, survived here and come to here. That is a great achievement, I can say that.
Sushma: And this is almost like, you know, you are almost near to that. There is, like, still natural trade equipment will be there, or it will be taken by Sandy. Thereafter, we can, you know, decide on that. So, still, the story is not yet completed, so still…
Swetcha: So sorry if that was an encrypted.
Sushma: direct feedback, because you are, you are good from among them, that's the reason you're still… you are just, you know, here.
Sushma: You just passed all those rounds and heals. That's it. Nothing more.
Sushma: Yeah, anything?
Swetcha: No, I'm done. Thank you so much for clarifying those things.
Sushma: Yeah, no worries. Over to you, Sandy.
Sandy: Hi, Swetcha. Is that how you pronounce my name?
Swetcha: It is, that's dot.
Sandy: Okay, I'm Sanjli, and I'll be starting with my questions. I hope I'm audible to you.
Swetcha: Yes.
Sandy: Suppose an employee comes to you, upset about not being promoted.
Sandy: They feel overlooked and demotivated. How would you handle the situation?
Swetcha: Okay, so when an employer is reaching out to me, it is very important to first understand their concern, like, what they're bringing to the table, and then you have to pinpoint the root cause, and since you're looking for an organizational psychologist, specifically.
Swetcha: So, a psychologist's role is to go beyond the company setup. Like, you actually need to go beyond the organization and understand the person.
Swetcha: at the level that they're standing, means, like, empathetically, you have to deal with the situation, and then you have to pinpoint the root cause of why they're feeling uncomfortable, and then, accordingly, you can give solutions to them.
Sandy: Okay, what kind of solution, if, you know, if you were in this scenario, what would you do? Like, as a solution? Other than, you know, all the things that you said, you know, acknowledging their feelings and…
Sandy: Except for that, what solution would you provide?
Swetcha: Hypothetically, they are not doing well in their job, like, they're not happy with what they're doing.
Sandy: window.
Swetcha: There's no commercial.
Sandy: Cloud Not being promoted.
Swetcha: they're upset about not being promoted, so we would give them the… we could give them the solutions to getting a promotion. We could tell them that these are the requirements for the role that they want to fulfill in the future, and
Swetcha: to fulfill that criteria, these are the steps that need to be taken. So, we talk to them on a personal level, and we also try to understand the root cause, that why are… why exactly are they not being promoted as of now.
Swetcha: If they are working good, and if there are some errors or some gaps between the position they are trying to fulfill and the one they're already doing, we just pinpoint to them that these are the skills that you are missing, and if you work on them, we would definitely look into the promotion.
Sandy: Okay.
Sandy: If an employee constantly interrupts others in team discussions, how would you handle it as an HR?
Swetcha: So, if someone is constantly trying to put a point forward, and it is being disrespectful to other people's opinions, it would definitely be…
Swetcha: a reason to… a reason to bring consequences to them about them. It is important to have a clear conversation that if you
Swetcha: have, and also it is very important to have a clear platform, I believe. If, like, someone feels like that, they're not giving their opinions correctly, and they feel the need to constantly disrupting other people's talks, so…
Swetcha: I think there should be a particular platform where they can
Swetcha: give their opinion so that they don't feel misheard, first of all, and if they continue doing that, I believe it would be… it would be best if we have one-on-one conversation with them, that this is not professional behavior, and this will not be tolerated, and give them a warning on it.
Sandy: Okay, okay.
Sandy: Imagine a scenario where management pressures you to quickly terminate an employee without following proper procedures. What would you do?
Swetcha: If the decision is coming from management, I would actually like to look at the actual reasons, because it is very important to have equal opportunity among an organization. So, if the reason is not justified, I don't believe that termination should be…
Swetcha: going through, but since it is coming from direct management, it needs to be looked into, but I don't think a decision as big as termination should be taken in
Swetcha: This… in this speed.
Sandy: Okay, in this question, the issue wasn't termination, it was they were doing it without forwarding proper procedures. They were asking you to do it quickly.
Sandy: So…
Swetcha: Yeah, they are asking to do it quickly, so I just believe that it… that is not okay. It, like, breaks the trust of the employer, and it,
Swetcha: ruins the reputation of the organization among the other potential candidates, I believe.
Swetcha: So it's just not ethical, and I wouldn't want to go through with that.
Sandy: Okay.
Sandy: If employees are hesitant to share ideas, how would you foster a culture of openness?
Swetcha: I believe when you want people to give in ideas and opinions, it is important to create a platform where they can express their opinions anonymously first, because anonymity is something that gives you space to actually
Swetcha: Be honest about your opinions. We can still, like, encourage people to be honest and be open about what they have to say, but anonymity, if we create that sense, it just became… it just becomes obvious that their opinions are actually mattered, no matter where they're actually coming from.
Sandy: Now I'll be starting with the organizational fit questions.
Swetcha: Okay.
Sandy: If a deadline is at risk because another team hasn't delivered their part, what would you do?
Swetcha: First, you need to communicate that, like, first you need to understand the gaps once again. I believe communication is the key to every problem in HR. So, first you need to understand the gaps and why that thing wasn't fulfilled, and for future escalations, you need to make sure that the deadlines are not
Swetcha: just met on the day of the deadlines. You really need to have internal deadlines as well, so that the process goes smoothly, and no gaps such as that.
Swetcha: Comes forth, but in the situation where the deadline is missed because some other department is not fulfilling their role properly, you just,
Swetcha: You just go and communicate to them that this problem is occurring because of you, and you need to…
Swetcha: Solve this on your end as well, and you will be the one who'll be held accountable for it.
Sandy: book.
Sandy: If you strongly disagree with a teammate's idea, but they are senior to you, How would you respond?
Swetcha: I believe.
Swetcha: It is not important, just because someone is senior to you, you have to agree to all their opinions. So…
Swetcha: I wouldn't just go ahead and tell them that you are wrong here, because that would just be unprofessional in many ways, and maybe disrespectful also, because
Swetcha: they do have seniority over you. First, you try to understand where they are actually coming from, from their experience, from their point of view. Why do they feel the way they are feeling right now? And then you put forward your point, not as a statement, but as a question, like…
Swetcha: I feel this way about the statement you just made, and am I right or wrong about this? So, you just have a discussion, you just have an open discussion where you are also putting forward your points without disrespecting their opinions.
Sandy: If you are stuck because a process is slowing you down, what would you do?
Swetcha: If something is slowing me down, I feel like whenever I am doing any tasks, my first go-to thing to do is break it down into smaller sections so that I know that what am I actually dealing with, and I prioritize accordingly. And if the… if…
Swetcha: on the roadmap of doing things, I feel like something is not working out for me.
Swetcha: I prefer to keep it in my,
Swetcha: keep it in a corner for a while, and deal with other things that are part of the priority list, maybe just as important, so that my brain has something new to do with, do, and it can actually reach the idea from a newer perspective, or…
Swetcha: If something is stuck, you can also always reach out to seniors or someone who can help you with it.
Sandy: Oh.
Sandy: If resources are limited, but expectations are high, how would you approach the problem?
Swetcha: So, high expectations are something that I believe every organization keeps in people. So, in…
Swetcha: a scenario of, resource limitation, it is important to make the most out of the resources that are already available to you.
Swetcha: So, that is what sustainability means, I believe, which A4G stands for, sustainable growth. So, you need to fulfill… you need to make sure that the resources that you are using are fulfilled properly, and
Swetcha: You just try to make the best out of them, and just reach the expectations from what you already have.
Sandy: Suppose you come across just, like, a situation where you've realized that you've made a problem.
Sandy: And… what are the further steps that you do?
Swetcha: First of all, I take accountability for it, because, causing problems, or…
Swetcha: Causing a mistake is a very human thing to do, so it is very important, once you realize that you've made a mistake, you take accountability for it, and it is something that I cannot solve on my level. If it is a bigger mess, I would like to reach out to someone in management, or someone
Swetcha: Who could help me with it, so…
Swetcha: These will be my steps for doing that.
Sandy: Okay. Thank you, Swetcha, that was all from my side.
Swetcha: Possession so much.
Sushma: I'll just drop your contact number for you.
Sushma: Drop your content number and email address.
Sushma: Am I audible to you?
Swetcha: Oh, yes, ma'am. In the chat box.
Sushma: Drop your contact number and email address in the chat box. If you got shortlisted, so you will… you will hear from us. If you didn't hear anything from us, you can consider that we just moved with someone else. If we moving with you, there are, you know.
Sushma: a smaller format, it's like, you know, a one…
Sushma: One to two rounds will be there, which is secondary row nitrated pitment, and the oil distribution round.
Swetcha: So after this also, there would… there might be further rounds.
Sushma: Yes, if you got shortlisted, oil discussion round will be there.
Swetcha: Alright, that makes sense, so… I just drop it in the chart books, right?
Swetcha: my details.
Swetcha: Oh, God.
Swetcha: Okay. May I leave now?
Sushma: Thank you, Swetcha.
Swetcha: Alright, thank you so much, it was a pleasure giving this interview.
Sandy: I feel like she didn't have the proper technical HR skills, but she is very good for, you know, psychology intern and secondary role HR.
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: she don't have even a single, one internship experience in HR, but, her answers make sense, actually. The previous one also, okay, but she's very practical as well, okay.
Sandy: Yeah, she has, like, proper HR, HR.
Sandy: Thank you.
Sushma: Okay.
Sandy: Three more I left, right?
Sushma: I Singh song, yeah, she's not coming.
Sushma: Summit, will you please turn on your video?
Sowmiya K R: Yeah, I'm sure.
Sushma: Okay, where are you from?
Sowmiya K R: I'm from Chennai, Tamernado.
Sushma: Oh.
Sushma: So… Do you speak or understand Hindu?
Sowmiya K R: I couldn't understand anything.
Sushma: Yeah, hi, Faye.
Sushma: online affix.
Sushma: Okay, so what do your father or mother do, and siblings?
Sowmiya K R: Yeah, ma'am. Actually, I have came from a nuclear family. It consists of my father, mother, and a brother. My father actually works as a supervisor in Kabul, and my mother is a home waiver, and my brother is currently studying from Sowa's.
Sushma: You're very spirit-like express, so while you're… I know from your… from English literature or something, while you're communicating, make sure that others are catching your points immediately.
Sowmiya K R: Can I…
Sushma: I mean, the bad thing.
Sushma: Okay. Let's see, tell me,
Sushma: Who… how will your career aspiration will be aligned to this internship or to this organization?
Sowmiya K R: Yes, ma'am. I have already done an internship in HR, that is from a L&D, from Learning and Development Department.
Sowmiya K R: So, there I have learned how organization actually works and overall organization study at all. I want to deep dive into human resource from end to end, from sourcing to onboarding, planning, everything I need to do. That's what's my current goal right now.
Sowmiya K R: So this internship, I think it will provide me, like, what, everything I have done in my future also. So I, I need to have a more specific when it comes to, like, I'm trying to slow down my face, give me a minute.
Sowmiya K R: Okay.
Sowmiya K R: Ma'am, in my older internship, what I do is… it is an organization, like, it's a bigger organization.
Sushma: Just give, keep your answers pretty short and crispy.
Sowmiya K R: Actually, in my older organization, I have been working in L&D, and already said in the department, what we do is, we need to align
Sowmiya K R: employees' goals with their organizational goals. Like, we need to align it. So this is my major… major predominant action I have been doing over there. But that internship made me to do… from a recruitment. I didn't do recruitment from the earlier stages, so now I want to do more recruitment. I have handled IT… I can assist recruitment. As interns, many of the companies won't able to allow interns to do major recruitments.
Sowmiya K R: So I have assisted recruitment, but here I wanted to learn more about, like.
Sushma: Alright, alright, alright. Tell me your college time limits.
Sowmiya K R: Yes, ma'am, that is… that is completely different. My college is completely flexible. You can go whenever you want, you can come out whenever you want.
Sowmiya K R: Their classes, they give you a timesheet that how you wanted to align it. If you want to attend the first class, you can attend. If you want to leave this again, you may leave. So it's completely flexible based on your time period, and you need to attend certain goals. Like, you need to attend. 100 hours of this class means for a semester, you need to attend. That's in your perspective.
Sushma: But actually, can you please tell me approximate time you mostly give the, commitment, time for your classes, the time frame, time slot, approximate time slot that you must require in the college?
Sowmiya K R: Approximately… 9 to 2.
Sowmiya K R: Or 8 to 1…
Sushma: Okay, so can you please tell me when you will be back from college to whom?
Sowmiya K R: With an offline, that's not work. Maybe 2.30, I don't have a PR.
Sushma: Every day, every day after completing your classes, you're saying that, whenever you would like to, if you want, you can… but I just want to know that, every day, mostly, like, you know, when you will be completing your college, and when you will be back from college to home.
Sowmiya K R: Most probably, I will complete my college one pay itself, and if without traffic, I will claim to my home around 1.30 or 1.45. If it is traffic, it will be 2-2.
Sushma: Okay, tell me what you're expecting from this internship.
Sowmiya K R: I need to learn… I need to gain more experience for these leaderships, from a recruitment part to handling documentation, etc, and HR software, and I also mentioned, you know, Giri that is that you have using research purpose AIs, like a deep search, Gemini.
Sowmiya K R: or any other AIs we can be able to utilize. So, I think AIs are the most predominant one in future generations, because many of the technological parts are nowadays becoming automated. So, I wanted to be more creative, and from that journey, I also know that we may not take more initiatives also. So, I wanted to be an entrepreneur also, HR intrapreneur. So, this gave me the immense opportunity to do and learn from
Sowmiya K R: my mistakes, and I have done many things with these organizations.
Sowmiya K R: over here.
Sushma: Do you have any interviews or offers in pipeline?
Sowmiya K R: Yeah, ma'am, I have an interview office in Pipeline, that is also a HR, but it's a full-time opportunity I have as HR executive in a channel-based company, it is an onset.
Sowmiya K R: So, because of my college opportunities, I'm not able to proceed it further, so only I…
Sowmiya K R: Focusing more on remote.
Sushma: But you said that your college savings is so flexible, so if you got the opportunity, if you will be getting an opportunity in full-time, why can't you, you know, take a permission and do that full-time?
Sowmiya K R: Yes, ma'am, but my college is too straight. They ask for CDC. If you have much higher CDC, they will give you flexibility to move over your time. You can go wherever, and you can do whatever you want. But if you have a lower CDC, they will never allow you.
Sushma: Is it, like, if someone having less than 100 hours?
Sushma: 100 hours per month? I didn't understand how it usually counts.
Sowmiya K R: Not per month, ma'am, per semester. We need to enroll for a semester.
Sushma: I'm assuming.
Sowmiya K R: That's true.
Sowmiya K R: We need to enroll for a set of subjects that we like, actually. If I want to become a HR on whatever the electives I need to choose, based on that elective, they, you know, give me a clock based, like, you need to do 100-hour sessions. So, that's your wish. Whenever you can available, you can attend from whatever stuffs you need, you can choose them.
Sowmiya K R: It's a lamasa.
Sushma: Okay. See, while I'm asking about, like, you know, Eric, you said that your college is not, like, you know, flexible thereafter, when I tell, like, you're saying the state, so what I have to consider in this?
Sowmiya K R: No need to worry. If it's considered as a regular college, it would be around 8 to 1, not more than one or two classes.
Sushma: Oh… Tell me your last drawn stipend from your previous internship.
Sowmiya K R: Yes, ma'am, I have come to get HR internship. No, I'm currently working in this house, so it's a HR internship from skill perspective, where I have earned around $15,000 per month.
Sowmiya K R: But it comes…
Sushma: 1-5.
Sowmiya K R: SMAM15, $15,000.
Sushma: Okay.
Sowmiya K R: Initially, it was not 15,000. Initially, they have started around 7,500 per month. Later, based on the performance and appraisals, it renewed around 15,000.
Sushma: Are you currently working in that, internship?
Sowmiya K R: I have currently been working over there, but when my college starts, I was able to.
Sushma: I just mentioned only one month you worked as HR Learning and Development intern May 2026 to June 26?
Sowmiya K R: that's because we aren't able to put the past… I need to put it in the present in my resume, but it's not updated, actually.
Sushma: Are you currently working there?
Sowmiya K R: Yeah, yes.
Sowmiya K R: I've currently been working.
Sushma: Okay, what's the college tan… what's the… The work timing's there.
Sowmiya K R: That's also remote one. You need to work for around a 10-hour per day.
Sowmiya K R: 10 to 9 are Pati.
Sushma: Okay, but what's the approximate time that's required to do that work? Like, team meeting?
Sowmiya K R: 8 to 6, 8 to 6 months.
Sowmiya K R: 8am to 6pm.
Sushma: 8am to 6 p.m.
Sowmiya K R: Yes.
Sushma: Internship Timings!
Sowmiya K R: Yes, ma'am, yes.
Sowmiya K R: That's really hard to hear. Actually, I was also shocked.
Sushma: And how are you managing 8am to 6pm, timings with the internship, along with the economic commitments?
Sowmiya K R: No, ma'am, for the past 1 or 2 months, I don't have academic, so I don't have any other commitments, so I've been fully involved in that internship, because it's a startup, like a Kickstarter, so they need more time from the interns to do jobs.
Sushma: Okay, now you're… are you going to college?
Sowmiya K R: Not now from… still, I have one or two weeks.
Sowmiya K R: For your…
Sushma: So, what's the tenure there? Internship tenure you committed with this present internship?
Sowmiya K R: Until my college opens, like, August 15th.
Sowmiya K R: Until August 15, I have a deluard.
Sushma: No, no, usually, what's the tenure there? Is it 3 months of internship program, 6 months, 2 months? Something will be there, na?
Sowmiya K R: Yeah, mom, it will be there, but it is a… I already mentioned it is a startup, right? So, they would extend… initially, they would say it would be a 2-month internship, and later they can extend it currently right now. So, if I start… if I apologize for the starter, the tenure has been hindered. If it is along, we can prolong it.
Sushma: You're so confusing me about the… about the college, commitment, and even the internship also. I don't know what I have to decide that. I have seen various, very… various answers from you. Okay, alright.
Sowmiya K R: So one year, the basic line here, the basic time is flexibility. Everything is flexibility. My college gives me flexibility, and internships also gives me flexibility. I can do whatever I want. It's… my internship is also remote, so I can do… it is… there is a 10-hour schedule. You can assign your time from… from what to what, that's your perspective.
Sowmiya K R: And my college is completely flexible, so you can learn based on the time schedule.
Sowmiya K R: There is no complete start to end time. That's… that's up to you.
Sushma: When you're expecting your stipend for this internship?
Sowmiya K R: I have already read the JD, so I'm comfortable with that stipend.
Sushma: Why are you comfortable with the stipend? This internship is a fixed timings. So far, your college is flexible, and your internship current doing is flexible.
Sushma: And the intent… these internship opportunities not at all flexible, it is fixed.
Sushma: And, the pay is also very low from the pay that what you're coming in the present, organization. Why are you willing to take that, and you're okay for that low pay?
Sowmiya K R: Yes, ma'am. Initially, I actually thought the learning is the most vigorous that you have. There's no need for money in these earlier stages of your… when you're joining your job, you don't need to look for your CTC or whatever your money you get, so I properly prefer the learning the first. And next, why I chose this organization is because I need to have something to motivate me to work a lot. If I work for any other company, of course, that would be gain for the organization, but not for the
Sowmiya K R: Society. If I were to be a worker for an organization or a foundation like this.
Sowmiya K R: that made me to think, okay, I'm doing something that will be good for the society also. So that instinct would make me to work a lot. And if it is considering AI, because I already have a strong background in AI, because I have done MBA with AI and Yamel integrated, and I have also done a certification related to AI, that is, generative AI from AWS.
Sowmiya K R: So I have a keen interest in AI and AI policy makers. I'm currently following this, and I have done a few case studies related to it, so that
Sowmiya K R: I focus… based on the lower pay, that doesn't matter for me, because I focused more on learning.
Sushma: Alright, so, Sowmia, that's it from our end.
Sushma: I think we are not going forward with the next round.
Sushma: Because, we are feeling that, because this internship is required from 3pm to 9pm, commitment is required.
Sushma: That may clashes with your current commitment and some other timings. So, because of that, availability and stability issues, we are not moving forward with the next round. I appreciate your time and interest. All the best for your future. Have a nice day.
Sowmiya K R: Can I still annotate?
Sushma: Yeah, please.
Sowmiya K R: Actually, I have been available for 3 tonight, because I've already set my… my… I haven't had accessibility over my time. My college will not be able to push me for that.
Sowmiya K R: So, I haven't be able to to it.
Sushma: You said that, you know, up to August 15, you need to be, complete that internship, and without continuing that internship, how you can start this internship, and the time will be clashes to you. That's the thing, we are not proceeding that.
Sowmiya K R: If you're not proceeding with me, I will ask for you, but I'm trying to justify what I have said. I have already had the resign period is just one or two days, because it's a startup. You just have to inform the founder that you are leading. So that's the major, major concern. If this internship starts, means I can be able to leave it within one or two days.
Sushma: See, that is our concern. If whatever you committed in your previous internship, that you were not completing the commitment there, how we believe that you will be committing… you will be completing.
Sowmiya K R: Yeah.
Sushma: post on the.
Sowmiya K R: I have all…
Sushma: In today's 8 months.
Sowmiya K R: Yeah, mom, I have already come.
Sushma: I didn't… I didn't… I didn't much convinced about your availability and stability, wise for this internship, which is very high of priority as a HR. So, when we hire someone, we have to, you know, also
Sushma: see that whether that person, integral person, is going to be, you know, continue with us for the next 6 months, the assurance that I didn't receive from you, even from this answer itself.
Sowmiya K R: Yeah, that's okay if you didn't trust me, I don't know. I can touch it.
Sushma: It's not… it's not at all trust. It's like, you know.
Sushma: yeah, convincing. The way I just, didn't convince that. That's it.
Sushma: Because the present intention, you're ready to leave, so that I'm assuming that, maybe in future also, if you get another opportunity, you definitely leave this one. So, that is something, my concern, that's it, nothing.
Sowmiya K R: Actually, I want to clarify it, I don't want to be selected at all, I don't want to convince you, because I wanted to clarify one thing, because I'm not leaving my organization
Sowmiya K R: not running my one… I have been assigned for so many tasks, I have been completed everything now. I have been working for a pipeline to set another intern for that job to do. So if the pipeline has been connected, and I don't have any other roles to be performed over there.
Sowmiya K R: So I have planned sessions, and then only I have it.
Sushma: All right, thanks for your confirmation and clarification. Have a nice day.
Sushma: She's like, you know, adjusting the answers like anything in.
Sandy: Good evening!
Sushma: Yay!
Sandy: She confused us also.
Sushma: Huh.
Sushma: See, I think for CEP630 is there how we are going… Can you please inform those Shivansh?
Sandy: Like, do you not?
Sushma: Yeah, do it in Zoom 1.
Sushma: And tell the Shivan, Shivan that you will be late for 15 minutes.
Sandy: Yeah, I'll inform.
Sushma: yashna, right?
yashna: Yes, ma'am.
Sushma: Okay. Hello, tell me.
Sushma: Where are you from, and what do your father, mother, do, and siblings?
yashna: Yeah, so, I'm from Haryana, but, like, my permanent address is in Punjab due to my father's job. He's in private, industry, he's in, security field. Like, he's, the HOD of security department.
yashna: So, like, recently, he's, like, in Trident Hills Real Estate Company. He's switching from Trident Hills to Brookfield in Ludhana. And, before that, he was in Taj, and my mother is housewife. My, I have one younger sibling, he is, in 12 standard.
Sushma: Okay.
yashna: Yo.
Sushma: Tell me, how will your career aspiration will be aligned to this internship? Or to this organization?
yashna: Sure. So, like I said in previous round, I'm doing my MBA in HR. So, obviously, I want to build my career in HR, and as much skills I can, gain from the internship, it will only help and upskill my performance in future. So, obviously, this internship will align perfectly with my career goals and my future,
yashna: career goals.
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: What's your last drawn stipend from your previous internship?
yashna: Actually, in Taj, they provide stipend for 6 months, and I was there for only 6 weeks. It was around for 45 days, so it was, like, unpaid, internship. If I had done for 6 months, I would be getting stipend, but it was unpaid internship.
Sushma: Okay.
yashna: Ew.
Sushma: What's the agent that you… that you committed and you completed?
yashna: Sorry?
Sushma: What's the internship tenure that you committed and completed there?
yashna: My, tenure was for 6 weeks, or around 45 days. So, it was from June 1st to July, 15, I guess. Yeah, last week itself, I got my internship certificate from the, like, touch.
Sushma: What's your college term means?
yashna: It's from 9 to 1.30, 1.30 or 2.
Sushma: At what time you moved back from college to home?
yashna: In 5 minutes, because my collagen is in Patiala, so I'm living at PG. So it's, like, almost only 5 minutes of distance. So, like, it's not time-consuming.
Sushma: Okay. When you will be going, like, you know.
Sushma: Going to complete your MBA. Is it 2027? Which month?
yashna: Around this month only, in May. In May, I will be having my finals, and around that time, I will be completing my, remaining one year of MBM.
Sushma: Okay.
yashna: Yes.
Sushma: Tell me what you're expecting from this internship.
yashna: So, from this internship, I am expecting a practical, experience, in HR field, so that I can enhance my,
yashna: experience, and, I have read the job description and all the responsibilities for the HR role in this organization, and I think it is perfectly aligned for me, and, which will, like, recruitment, onboarding, and, collaborate… collaboration with, the other teams and people, like.
yashna: it is something which I'm aspiring from, and which I'm inclined towards. So, that's all the things I'm expecting from this internship.
Sushma: Okay.
yashna: Yes.
Sushma: Do you have any interviews or offers in pipeline?
yashna: I am actually, I have some, one or two interviews, like, aligned, but, right now I don't have any, offer. I did have, but, like, it was some target-based,
yashna: offer, like, if you hire this much, employees, you will get… yeah, so I didn't want to get in that, type of internship, so, like, I didn't, like, I didn't join them, so yeah.
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: do you have any other commitments, like any online or offline courses, or any other freelancing work?
Sushma: Any other internship commitment?
yashna: No, actually, I was planning, like, I had two options in my mind after completing my Taj internship, that either I will go for any course, but my main priority was to get an internship so that, I don't waste my one year of MBA time, because
yashna: After completing MBA, when you apply to companies, they already expect that you have experience of 6 months to 1 year.
yashna: So, if I'm not doing any internship or work during my one year, or remaining one year, so, like, it will be, I think, not productive. So, my main priority is to get an internship. If I get this opportunity, obviously this will be my priority, and I will not be doing any other courses.
yashna: So, yeah, that's pretty much… I'm…
Sushma: Did you come to Ringdanship at Taj? I was still doing? Yes. I was still doing?
yashna: Ann, it's completed. It's… I told you, it's completed last week itself.
Sushma: Okay.
yashna: Yeah, I received my certificate on, Saturday last week. Last week, or I guess last to last week.
Sushma: Are you… if you got short Eshita, are you comfortable of, committing 6 months.
yashna: Yeah, it's, perfectly, okay with me, because for other internships, I was, like, looking, they were asking for more, hours, which was also okay, because I want to do this, I want to work, so, like, 6 hours, like, 3 to 9… I guess 3 to 9 is the timing, right?
yashna: Yeah, it's perfectly okay with me, because I can balance my college also, and then my internship also, so it will not be collapsing with each other.
Sushma: Okay.
yashna: Ew.
Sushma: Any questions that you would like to ask?
yashna: So, like, if I get, selected, so when it will be, like, starting, what will be the, like, timings, what will be the starting date and all? I wanted to know.
Sushma: If you got shortlisted, next week, your onboarding will start, like, mostly because after this, there is, like, you know, two… two more rounds will be there, if you got shortlisted, so…
Sushma: So if you… if you hear from us, you will continue for that process. If you didn't hear from us, you can consider that we just move with someone else.
yashna: Okay, so will there be any training period, or, like, just… Straight into the internship.
Sushma: Trying, yeah, training on work will be given, training along with the work will be given.
yashna: Oh, thank you.
Sushma: After downloading.
yashna: Okay.
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: Over to you, Sandy.
Sushma: Disha, could you please join Room 3?
Sandy: Hi, yashna, I hope I'm audible to you.
yashna: Yeah, hi, Sandy.
Sandy: So I'll be starting with my questions. So my first question to you is, suppose an employee comes to you.
Sandy: Upset about not being promoted. They feel overlooked and demotivated. How would you handle the situation?
yashna: Overlooked and remodeled. Okay, so, like, I would, obviously listen to their concern first, on the whole concern, and, I will, obviously ask my, the senior manager, like, what was the reason for the delay of promotion? If, like, the reason is, related to their performance.
yashna: or if they're not performing up to the mark, then I will, like,
yashna: like, go through that, reason, and I will explain to the employee, and will, like, give them the options, like, how you can improve yourself, and not demotivate yourself, so that in future, you can obviously go for the promotion. There will be no such, delays in your promotion if you, do your work up to the mark.
Sandy: Okay.
Sandy: If an employee constantly interrupts others in team discussions, how would you handle it?
yashna: So, if an employee do such things, at first, I will not point that employee in front of everyone so that he does not feel, like, isolated or, embarrassed. I… after the meeting, I will,
yashna: like, talk to the employee, and, like, know the reason why they are doing it. If it is, like, their habit, or they're doing, like, unknowingly, I will, like, point them out, and I will, explain them in such a way so that they don't feel offensive, and they will take it in a positive way, so that they don't disturb others also, and it will, like, like, how they can reflect on themselves also, that what they are doing
yashna: Singh room.
Sandy: Oh, two equally qualified candidates are final round choices for a role.
Sandy: One is a culture fit, and the other one has slightly stronger technical skills. Whom do you hire?
yashna: Okay, so in this case, either I can go for, like, how much experience they have, if, like, someone has an edge over the experience, I can go for that employee. And, if I think,
yashna: someone… if they both have the same experience level, so that, I can go with the technical one, because we can train them to be a culture fit for the organization, but the one who is only culturally fit and not technically skilled upskilled, I can… we cannot, like, do them the upskilling for the technical requirements. We can do it
yashna: up to a certain level only, so I would go with the technical one.
Sandy: If employee engagement scores are dropping.
yashna: True.
Sandy: Shita, would you start to improve them?
yashna: So, yeah, this I've also faced personally while my, like, during my internship. Employers first, like, they hesitate to participate in the employee engagement activities, but when they see others, joining and they are having fun, they automatically comes and volunteer themselves to participate in the games.
yashna: So, what we can do is.
yashna: first, like, understand what is the basic reason they are not participating themselves. And, like, main of the reasons, some of the main reasons are, like, they are, like, not, like, it's,
yashna: like, extrovert, and they're not, like, they don't want to spend more time in such activities, or they're not just… they're just generally shy. So, if these are such a reasons, we have to conduct, activities in such a way so that everyone feels included, and they don't have to, like, individually don't have to come out, and they can enjoy in-group, activities.
yashna: These, these are the ways we can do, to increase the employee engagement.
Sandy: Okay, thank you, yashna, that was all from my side.
yashna: Thank you.
Sushma: So, Eshna, if you got short tested, you will get…
Sushma: They call from us. If you didn't get any call from us, you can consider that, we just move with someone else.
yashna: Okay, okay.
Sushma: We appreciate, yeah, thanks for your time, and have a nice day.
yashna: Thank you, thank you, have a good time.
Sandy: Thank you.
Sandy: Oh.
Sushma: Right. So that is, I mean, I was about to say that if you're good… if you're good to go, then only go ahead, or the rest is.
Sandy: Yeah.
Sushma: Oh, hi, Eshita.
Sushma: Where are you from Eshita?
Sushma: Unmute yourself.
Sandy: Eshita, you're on mute.
Sushma: Mute yourself, you're in mute.
Eshita Singh: Good afternoon, ma'am. Sorry, good evening, ma'am.
Sushma: Yeah, good evening. Where are you from?
Eshita Singh: Basically, ma'am, my hometown is Baranzi, but I'm currently living in Lucknow.
Sushma: Got it. What's your father, mother, do, and siblings?
Eshita Singh: My… I have, one…
Eshita Singh: brother and one sister. They are smaller than me, and my father is a, like, men…
Eshita Singh: Like, in the… corporate world, wherein he have to do, like, a partnership with a
Eshita Singh: Government in order to make the, house and everything.
Eshita Singh: Basically, the contract… contract type of work. And my mother is teacher.
Eshita Singh: In a government escape.
Sushma: alone.
Sushma: Alright.
Sushma: So… Okay, let me check here…
Sushma: What's your last drawn statin from your previous internship?
Eshita Singh: Currently, the internship which I'm currently pursuing, basically, it is, like, per month I'm getting 5,000 rupees.
Eshita Singh: And this internship would go… would last…
Sushma: So your present internship that which you joined in June 2026, right? Last month.
Sandy: I think her video is frozen.
Sushma: Yes, yes.
Sushma: Oh.
Sushma: Sorry, Eshita?
Sushma: Let's wait 2 to 3 minutes. She's coming, she's back.
Sushma: Eshita, could you please turn on your video and unmute yourself?
Sushma: Did you inform to Shiva and Sandy?
Sushma: It's 6.30.
Sushma: If he waits 5 minutes, we can, you know…
Sushma: wrap this also. So, tell him to wait for 5 minutes to start the appointment, instead of scheduling another one.
Sandy: I had texted him, but he hasn't replied only, so…
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: Alright.
Sandy: He's asking, should I switch? I should tell him to wait now, then.
Sushma: Just wait for 5 minutes.
Sushma: We will become cheating here.
Sushma: I just want to wait up to 6.35.
Sandy: Then later.
Sushma: Eshita, we will wait, please resolve that.
Eshita Singh: Sorry, ma'am, it was network issue.
Sushma: Okay, see, Eshita, my question to you is, you're currently doing an internship, so you joined last month, and what's the tenure there you committed?
Eshita Singh: Around 4 hours.
Eshita Singh: covering for us there. It is, like, time are… time's… time is not my concern for your internship, because I will give.
Sushma: So, I'm.
Eshita Singh: Whatever you're asking.
Sushma: I'm asking the tenure, the internship tenure that you committed, in the present internship.
Eshita Singh: Yes, ma'am?
Eshita Singh: So it's, yes, I started…
Eshita Singh: And June, July, and August would be the end.
Sushma: August will be the end date, okay. And what is your internship timings there?
Eshita Singh: The timing is basically on my concern, so it is flexible. I just have to give 4 hours a day.
Sushma: Even though if it is flexible, what, like, can you please tell me which window you usually, you know, do that for hours? Is it, like, morning, afternoon, or evening? Because, what's your college time?
Eshita Singh: No, ma'am, my college is already completed, so there is no college issues.
Sushma: When did you complete your college?
Eshita Singh: MBA, I completed in 26, and the result is already out by July.
Sushma: Is it UG or PZ you completed?
Eshita Singh: MBA.
Sushma: So, what's your next plan, then?
Eshita Singh: So, maybe I'm trying to, like, get a fixed job, but for HR…
Eshita Singh: that I need a lot of experience beforehand. So, for… I'm searching experience.
Sushma: Are you not looking full-time roles?
Eshita Singh: As I said, I am looking for a full-time job, but HR needs a lot of experience, hence I'm doing these small internship time.
Sushma: Okay.
Eshita Singh: Yes, ma'am.
Sushma: But sir, you already have…
Sushma: two internship in hand for experience. Still, why are you looking on another internship in hand? And currently, you're doing one internship, and why you would like to do… while you would like to, you know, commit another internship.
Eshita Singh: Because whenever I apply whatever…
Eshita Singh: wherein I want to work as an HR, they ask for experience of one year at least. So, for getting that one year experience, probably I can do, like, a month internship and recognized.
Eshita Singh: So, basically, $5,000 per month.
Sushma: Oh, alright. So…
Sushma: Eshita, like, currently you're doing some internship, so, you know, 4 hours with flexible is also, yeah, challenging.
Sushma: And for you here, 3pm to 9pm is very required as a HR. I was thinking that there will be clashes for your present internship and this internship. So for that reason, we cannot move forward, you know, with the next step.
Sushma: Because if you complete that internship, please complete that internship completely, and after, if you would like to, you know,
Eshita Singh: Joy.
Sushma: intern with us, you can, you know, reapply for future openings.
Eshita Singh: Okay, ma'am. Can you let me know who is selected from your side?
Sushma: No, it's like, we need to evaluate that, which I can, Rance, yeah,
Eshita Singh: Okay, okay, no problem, ma'am.
Eshita Singh: Have a nice day.
Sushma: Have a nice day.
Eshita Singh: Same to you, ma'am.
Eshita Singh: Yay.
Sushma: Yeah, and also your internet also is, like, you know, dragging, and it's very difficult for us also. But, but this is the main reason, like, you know, you were, maybe clashes with ours, that is the main reason.
Eshita Singh: Basically, today is my internet not working because outside it's heavy raining, so that's why.
Sushma: Yeah, yeah. But I appreciate your time and interest and patience, so all the best for the future. Have a nice day to you.
Eshita Singh: Thank you, ma'am.
Eshita Singh: May I leave the meeting now?
Sushma: You can leave them meat.
Eshita Singh: Thank you, ma'am.
Sushma: So Sandy.